<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wyatt Winters | Saving the world one computer at a time</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wyattwinters.com/</id><updated>2015-05-18T09:53:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>BizLegFoss Final Exam</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/bizlegfoss-final-exam.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-18T09:53:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-05-18:bizlegfoss-final-exam.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What a delightfully bizarre class this has been. Assignments that were sometimes made up on the fly, due dates that were more rough suggestions than actual deadlines, 3 times more blog posts than I have ever made in my life, and about 5 weeks of IRC classes. While I can't say I enjoyed every minute of it, it was still quite an experience. So, in the appropriate fashion, the final exam of the class is a blog post. I wonder how many other classes at RIT has a blog-post-final-exam. It's probably 0, right? Anyways, after this long and unnecessary introduction paragraph, it's time to answer these questions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When does code you create become copyrighted?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you save it out to a file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could wave a magic wand, and open source any piece of proprietary software, what software would you choose?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As cars become more and more computers with some neat peripherals attached (like steering columns, gasoline engines, and wheels), the software that powers cars should be open sourced. By extension, that software should be easily user-upgradeable, since security patches seem like they would be &lt;em&gt;pretty dang important&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the software above was open sourced, would it’s [&lt;a href="http://www.homestarrunner.com/sbemail89.html" target="_blank"&gt;sic&lt;/a&gt;] company remain stable? How would the company continue to make money?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is like the ultimate form of widget frosting, so I imagine car companies would be perfectly fine, if not slightly higher sales from &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hardcore hackers who want to develop &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;for cars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The future is now! Or at least in my imagination!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you feel like was the most beneficial thing to learn in the class?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a much better grasp of the various OSI licenses available to me. More accurately, I now have enough of a grasp to just use GPLv2 and hope nothing explodes. Licenses are complicated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain the some of the motivations a company may have to open source software. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm quite tempted to just link to &lt;a href="http://opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php" target="_blank"&gt;the reading&lt;/a&gt; this question &lt;em&gt;clearly&lt;/em&gt; is derived from and leave it at that, but I won't. I will instead copy and paste from it, and since I have now linked to it, I have fulfilled the BY portion of the CC license. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Start block quote&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantage: Development Speed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It follows that commercial developers leveraging the bazaar mode should be able to grab, and keep, a substantial initiative advantage over those that don't. But there's more; the first commercial developer in a given market niche to switch to this mode may gain substantial advantages over later ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Because the pool of talent available for bazaar recruitment is limited. The first bazaar project in a given niche is more likely to attract the best co-developers to invest time in it. Once they've invested the time, they're more likely to stick with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantage: Lower Overhead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switching to the open-source model should also be good for a significant overhead reduction in per-project software production costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open-source model allows software shops to (in effect) outsource some of their work, paying for it in values less tangible than money. (But perhaps not less economically significant; the increased speed with which an outside co-developer can have a needed bug fix will often translate into a substantial opportunity gain for that customer.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means smaller shops will be able to handle bigger projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantage: Closeness to the Customer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most often-repeated pieces of management advice is "Stay close to the customer." In today's fast-moving, short-product-cycle business climate it's more important than ever to do that - to understand almost as soon as they do what the customers want and be able to rapidly respond to those needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sell software, what better way to do this than by co-opting your customers' engineers to help your development?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth pointing out that the open-source, bazaar method resembles the way many successful Japanese companies have done consumer product development; get a product to market that works but is not perfect, and iterate quickly based upon customer feedback to reach the combination of features that the customers need and want. This has turned out to be especially valuable for high technology products (laptops, personal assistants, cellphones, etc) that people don't know they need, or what features they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantage: Broader Market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important side-effect of the open-source model will be a much wider platform range for your product. Open-source authors frequently find themselves receving [sic], for free, port changes for operating systems and environments they barely know exist and can't afford developers to support. Each such port, of course, widens the market appeal of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;end block quote (Hurrah for Creative Commons!)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any changes you would suggest making to the profile template?  What parts did you find most interesting or important?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The EFF section (as much as I love them) seems a bit out of place. It feels like most of it is covered to various extents in previous sections of the template. As such, the EFF section just feels liked a tacked on afterthought. I found the questions related to community architecture and repo structures the most interesting. I've often found that the hardest part of getting into a given open source project is figuring out just where the hell to go to either get source code, file bugs, or just get started in general. Speaking of filing bugs, why isn't there a section for listing the bug tracker(s) URL? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you could have spent more time, say an extra week, on any topic, which 
would you have liked to cover more in depth?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would say licenses. I feel like we went just deep enough where I feel like I have an understanding, but then I forget one key thing and end up getting sued somehow. I feel like there's a weird level of understanding in many fields where you &lt;em&gt;just enough&lt;/em&gt; to seem knowledgeable, then people assume you know what you're talking about and you get deep into a rabbit hole. Maybe that's just me. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are you using license &lt;strong&gt;insert license X here&lt;/strong&gt;  for your open source project?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't actually have a lot of actual open source projects, but my only "real" project is under public domain. This is before I knew the intricacies of the "real" OSI licenses, and I don't really care what people end up doing with the project anyway. If someone can turn that pile of barely functional garbage into a commercial project, then go for it. I would be quite impressed, honestly. All that being said, I still really like the WTFPL. That's the sort of legally binding license I can get behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you would suggest a video to be watched as part of this course, what would it be?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JlIrSMzF8T4" target="_blank"&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; explains the difference between the GPL and the LGPL pretty well. He's also a real actual lawyer (or at least his lower third says he is), so that's pretty neat. That video by itself probably wouldn't constitute a vidreview, but &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC58hHLmRo3kEcCqJRBO2qKg/videos"&gt;his channel&lt;/a&gt; has a whole boatload of licensing related videos, and some other fun startup related stuff (which may or may not be relevant to this course). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, that was pretty painless. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 14</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-14.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-10T12:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-05-10:foscis-week-14.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh man! It's the last one of these! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.law.umaryland.edu/faculty/profiles/faculty.html?facultynum=984" target="_blank"&gt;Frank Pasquale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/opinion/the-dark-market-for-personal-data.html" target="_blank"&gt;"The Dark Market for Personal Data"&lt;/a&gt; (NYTimes paywall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://balkin.blogspot.com/2014/09/interview-on-black-box-society_19.html" target="_blank"&gt;Interview on The Black Box Society"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/opinion/the-dark-market-for-personal-data.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/10/17/opinion/the-dark-market-for-personal-data.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://balkin.blogspot.com/2014/09/interview-on-black-box-society_19.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://balkin.blogspot.com/2014/09/interview-on-black-box-society_19.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-10-16 for the article, 2014-09-19 for the interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Dark Market for Personal Data" is pretty much as it says on the tin. It covers the secretive world of data brokers, and the numerous perils of their systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Interview on The Black Box Society" provides background on the book, and insights into some of the decisions / thought processes of the author.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Scurrilous" is a wonderful word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I would like to embrace data brokers for the dystopian cyberpunk future they're inevitably leading us to, that would be with the condition they actually know what the hell they're doing. If their lists and data are wrong half the time, they don't really accomplish much, and just make things worse for people they wrongly categorize. Until they get their data algorithms fixed, they probably should be regulated more heavily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That art (?) on the sidebar of the article is pretty great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, or Hipaa" Not quite there Frank. Acronyms are generally all caps, yeah? What sort of editor didn't catch that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"These problems can’t be solved with existing law." Three paragraphs later: "Privacy protections in other areas of the law can and should be extended to cover consumer data." &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The book’s method of analysis--could you explain it?" That's an awkwardly phrased question, isn't it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has there been any legal progress on data brokers since these articles were published?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What other lists are compiled by data brokers? I imagine there's some pretty specific stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you buy your own data from data brokers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This just seems like another set of articles that could be summed up as "Bad stuff is bad. I do not like bad stuff. Here is why. Now you also do not like bad stuff." I know I'm dreadfully cynical, but a large number of the articles I've read for this course have been incredibly similar. I don't know if that's the bias of the professor, or if all the commentary around tech issues is this homogeneous. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Open Source Exams?</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/open-source-exams.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-05T11:54:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-05-05:open-source-exams.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As BIZLEGFOSS wraps up, so approaches the final "exam". However, this exam is less typical than most, in that we (the students) get to help write it? At least that's what I think is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, here's my 3 suggestions for questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What topic/subject/section would you want to expand on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What topic/subject/section would you want to remove / minimize?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was your least favorite part of the course?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine a lot of the other responses will be pretty similar, but there you are.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 13</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-03T12:05:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-05-03:foscis-week-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh jeeze, another week with four things. One of which is a video. Goodness. Yet somehow, next week doesn't have anything assigned? How strange. Maybe someone deleted it from the wiki I ported this from? &lt;em&gt;Who knows?!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://about.me/slavin" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Slavin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Kroft" target="_blank"&gt;Steve Kroft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adrian_Chen" target="_blank"&gt;Adrian Chen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenewinquiry.com/author/david-a-banks/" target="_blank"&gt;David A. Banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_slavin_how_algorithms_shape_our_world" target="_blank"&gt;"How algorithms shape our world"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/michael-lewis-stock-market-rigged-flash-boys-60-minutes/" target="_blank"&gt;"Is the US Stock Market rigged?"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/190369/truth-about-anonymouss-activism" target="_blank"&gt;"The Truth About Anonymous’s Activism"&lt;/a&gt; [sic]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/naming-nameless/" target="_blank"&gt;"Naming Nameless"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_slavin_how_algorithms_shape_our_world" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_slavin_how_algorithms_shape_our_world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/michael-lewis-stock-market-rigged-flash-boys-60-minutes/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.cbsnews.com/news/michael-lewis-stock-market-rigged-flash-boys-60-minutes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/190369/truth-about-anonymouss-activism" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.thenation.com/article/190369/truth-about-anonymouss-activism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/naming-nameless/" target="_blank"&gt;http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/naming-nameless/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The TED talk was filmed July 2011&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;August 17, 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;December 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 18, 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How algorithms shape our world" covers the rapid spread of algorithms into every aspect of life, even so far as to inspire terraforming to speed up those algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Is the US Stock Market rigged?" covers the spread of algorithms into the magical world of the stock market, and it's "rigging" of the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Truth About Anonymous’s Activism" and "Naming Nameless" are both essentially book reviews of "Hacker, Hoaxer, Whistleblower, Spy: The Many Faces of Anonymous".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The TED talk was engaging and humorous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is entirely unrelated to pretty much anything, but I really like the idea of a "BATS Exchange". I'm sure it stands for something, but the idea of a stock exchange purely for bats and bat-related products is pretty funny. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "Naming Nameless": "Perhaps the best way to confront Anonymous is not as a subject in a controlled study but as an environment to be understood."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "Is the US Stock Market rigged?": "robot computers". Let that sink in. Not just robots, not just computers, but ROBOT COMPUTERS!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's perhaps against the spirit of those whole exercise, but can I just put the entirety of "The Truth About Anonymous’s Activism" as a bad point? This first paragraph is something else. Oh, it gets even better: "Lulz, a corruption of "LOL". &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's like they haven't even seen that Fox News video!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Everything about this article seems ill-advised. Goodness. Also, the possessive form of "Anonymous" would be "Anonymous'". &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "Naming Nameless": "That asshole that showed up to your prison-abolition march in a Guy Fawkes mask and started shouting about the Fed? That was probably Anonymous too." I mean, in so much that "Anonymous" doesn't formally exist, sure. You could also argue that &lt;em&gt;everyone else&lt;/em&gt; is also "probably Anonymous," just a different part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is the algorithm-aziation of the world a net positive, or a net negative?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do people seem so intent on making sweeping generalizations about an organization as large (and as loose) as Anonymous? Sure, they are quite an interesting group (or group of groups, depending on how you look at it), but what do we gain out of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is "doxxing" spelled with one x or two?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"How algorithms shape our world"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't really understand why this talk was presented. Yes, there are algorithms on the backend of virtually every system in the world today. So, what next then? Do we blow up all the computers? Do we go deeper down the rabbit hole? Do we make vaguely-interesting speeches?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Is the US Stock Market rigged?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial industry is broken? Weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Truth About Anonymous’s Activism" + "Naming Nameless"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I lumped these two articles together because they feel like the same thing, written by different people. I think the main problem I have with both writing about Anonymous and writing about those who write about Anonymous (which in itself is a little silly) is that Anonymous by its very nature is impossible to define. As such, how the hell does one right about it? Ms. Coleman apparently found enough to fill a book (which I have not read, so perhaps all these arguments are invalidated somehow), but what is to be gained from it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also feel like there is some sort of defensive aspect to this. I really like the internet, warts and all. It sounds stupid, but it feels less exciting and magical when we have anthropologists and other social science people coming in and trying to categorize and lump everyone into different camps. Why can't you just let the internet do its thing and be weird? Where everyone belongs dozens to hundreds of groups, without worrying about "fitting in"? I understand that the internet is becoming more and more "normal" every day, but the fact that someone can get &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; into rabbit holes about almost any topic on the planet is still pretty fantastic. It's hard to articulate, but I think trying to "study" the internet and internet communities does a disservice to everyone involved. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 12</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-12.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-26T16:03:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-26:foscis-week-12.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Man, this week is jam-packed with stuff to read. It's not all that much in terms of word count, but it makes the writing-about-it part difficult. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astra Taylor + Joanne McNeill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://igm.rit.edu/%7Eandy/" target="_blank"&gt;Andy Phelps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://gabriellacoleman.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Gabriella Coleman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Dads of Tech"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"A Few Thoughts on GamerGate"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Why the World Needs Anonymous" + "My Hacker, My Source, My Snitch"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thebaffler.com/salvos/dads-tech" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.thebaffler.com/salvos/dads-tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@Andy_at_RITMAGIC/a-few-thoughts-on-gamergate-62c151c0eebb" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/@Andy_at_RITMAGIC/a-few-thoughts-on-gamergate-62c151c0eebb&lt;/a&gt; (Man, medium.com sure has some ugly URLs.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/532381/why-the-world-needs-anonymous/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.technologyreview.com/view/532381/why-the-world-needs-anonymous/&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href="https://medium.com/backchannel/my-best-hacker-source-was-snitching-for-the-feds-68414d6b552a" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/backchannel/my-best-hacker-source-was-snitching-for-the-feds-68414d6b552a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unknown, sometime in 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"2014-10-22T14:53:11.613Z" (medium.com won't tell you, unless you dig into the source. What?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;November 7, 2014 + "2014-11-10T14:42:27.951Z" (Seriously, medium. People like dates on articles. EDIT: It's light grey on white on the bottom status bar. Nice work guys.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Dads of Tech" - A discussion of how the entire technology industry is run by old white dudes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"A Few Thoughts on GamerGate" - As it says on the tin, thoughts about Gamergate, and the significant negative repercussions on the games industry as a whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Why the World Needs Anonymous" - Again, as it says on the tin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"My Hacker, My Source, My Snitch" - An past-tense interview / retrospective with "Sabu", the FBI Informant / Anon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "A Few Thoughts on GamerGate": "understanding that just because the internet makes certain behaviors possible, it doesn't make them morally or ethically appropriate"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "Why the World Needs Anonymous": "you should care because Anonymous functions as a social laboratory where participants experiment with the power, threat, and promise of anonymity itself."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "My Hacker, My Source, My Snitch": "tearing them a new network interface".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "The Dads of Tech": "mansplain". First sentence in, and I'm already off-board. It's not even a clever portmanteau. Those two words don't have any sounds in common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "A Few Thoughts on GamerGate": "WikiPedia". Oh dear, Mr. Phelps. Oh dear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From "The Dads of Tech": This is probably short-sighted and awful of me, because (believe it or not) I'm not a female in the technology industry, but man, do you need to write that much over such a problem? Yes, I understand things are unpleasant for females / non-males in the tech industry. I'm not sure that such angry articles are going to be read by your target audience, nor change their behaviors. It seems like a fools errand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the Internet continues to form overlapping communities, is it prudent to try and label "groups" at this point? A single user can have affiliations with numerous groups and sites, so much so that labeling them "Anonymous" or "SJW" isn't really productive, or even completely accurate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there anything individuals can do to help the "patriarchy" of the tech industry? (Besides not being a jerk, of course.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's up with gamergate these days? Is it still going on? Are people still being assholes? It kind of fell off the radar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Dads of Tech"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I mentioned it in "The Bad", but I don't understand why so many of these kinds of articles exist. I mean, yes, things are bad for some groups of people. This is true throughout the world, throughout industries and larger groups of people. Yes, things should be better. But most of the time, these articles seem to preach to the choir, both in terms of actual writing, and the usual audience for them. I generally try to avoid the news as much as possible (since it's usually awful and depressing), so maybe these type of articles are fixing the world without my noticing. But I doubt it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A Few Thoughts on GamerGate"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article is very much in the same vein as the last. I just don't see the point of complaining about assholes (on the internet or otherwise). You probably aren't going to "fix" them. The only thing one can do is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; be an asshole, and try to offset the hate and anger that assholes do put into the world. At a certain point, it becomes a matter of "don't feed the trolls". &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Why the World Needs Anonymous" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short, sweet, and well written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"My Hacker, My Source, My Snitch"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, well written, and fascinating. Somehow I managed to miss most of this whole fiasco. Or perhaps I didn't miss it, but simply forgot it as more and more nonsense was piled into my brain. Regardless, an interesting read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 11</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-11.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-19T11:24:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-19:foscis-week-11.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oddletters.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Molly Sauter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 1 and 3 of &lt;em&gt;The Coming Swarm&lt;/em&gt;. The contents of chapter 2 shall remain a mystery, for some reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/folderview?id=0BxvDQ-4qQO6dTUN5S3h6Mm1hOEk&amp;amp;usp=sharing" target="_blank"&gt;This random Google Drive link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The book is copyright 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 discusses the similarities and differences between DDoS and "classical" civil disobedience techniques. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 discusses the role of the mass media in the success of a DDoS attack as a political act.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3 had some excellent history, most of which I didn't previously know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"if the actions taken by activists don't "look like" activism, or the views presented are too outside the mainstream to appeal to viewers - and advertisers - it is likely that these actions will not be covered at all."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really liked the bit with "hacker-as-folk-devil."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1 is yet again rife with philosophical and social scientific madness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess it's common in these "academic" type books, but the constant "as &amp;lt;name&gt; says, &amp;lt;something&gt;" gets a little difficult to read. If your book is just a bundle of other people's work, why did you write a book? This is less of an issue in Chapter 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Activist DDoS actions and other types of disruptive activism are not random acts of vandalism; they are not simply shouting someone down with nonsensical noise." - I mean, "shouting someone down with nonsensical noise" is kind of the definition of a DDoS attack. I understand what Ms. Sauter means, but it's poorly phrased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are all DDoS attacks political in nature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As DDoS mitigation (very slowly) improves, what's the next "online civil disobedience" method of choice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I'm always super negative with these reviews. This week was &lt;em&gt;vastly&lt;/em&gt; better than previous weeks, but still wasn't fantastic. My main point of contention is that &lt;em&gt;politically motivated&lt;/em&gt; DDoS attacks seem super rare, and even then, the political ties are shaky at best. The most recent Github DDoS was barely political, the Lizard Squad DDoS of PSN / Xbox Live over Christmas was &lt;em&gt;barely&lt;/em&gt; political (I vaguely heard them whining about corporate greed or some such nonsense at one point). Getting a good DDoS going is pretty trivial at this point - one can rent time on botnets pretty easily, or even buy "stress testing" services and point them wherever. DDoS is practically commonplace at this point, so they aren't nearly as special or worthy of attention anymore. I think that severely mitigates their political potential. The writing itself was fine, but I find the premise a little flawed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 10</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-10.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-12T19:24:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-12:foscis-week-10.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://socgen.ucla.edu/people/christopher-kelty/" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Kelty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_2014_Fog_of_Freedom.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;"The Fog of Freedom"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_2014_Fog_of_Freedom.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_2014_Fog_of_Freedom.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article covers the development of general purpose computing and the ways it influenced (both positively and negatively) "freedom" (in various interpretations of the word).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition to being a really stupid acronym (which I'm a huge fan of), the WELL is apparently still running: &lt;a href="http://www.well.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.well.com/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;""You lack political liberty or freedom only if you are prevented from attaining your goal by human beings” (Berlin 1958, 7)."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"J. C. R. Licklider" is a really funny name. Granted, he was pretty influential in computing history, but man. "Licklider".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can't see the phrase "serious business" without giggling. Thanks internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I would like to do that by reference to a third domain: that of political philosophy." Oh, jeeze man, can you not? I'm still recovering from last week...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oddly enough, this is an article where I &lt;em&gt;dislike&lt;/em&gt; the frequent footnotes and annotations. When every other sentence is "Author (year)," it's hard to distinguish the original ideas in the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The acronyms "STS" and "MCS" are used like I am expected to know what they are. It took me a good couple minutes until I figured out they stand for "Science and Technology Studies" and "Media and Communications Studies" respectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article makes frequent use of the phrase "high tech industry". Is the low tech industry vibrant enough that the distinction is needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"smartphones (note the focus on augmented intelligence in the very name)" - I thought the "smart" in "smartphone" referred to the phone itself. What's the etymology behind the term?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This text seems intent on slapping labels (such as "libertarian") on various technologies. Why is labeling things so important in philosophy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had hopes for this week. Maybe we would be out of philosophy-town. We are not out of philosophy town. That being said, it was still more readable than last week's assignment. There were a handful of fun computing history facts, but the majority of it was still philosophical madness. I can't tell if I'm getting a subpar version of this course by doing it as an independent study, or the "real" version of this course is equally baffling and crazy. We may never know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Teamprop3</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/teamprop3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-09T17:41:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-09:teamprop3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Team Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Email&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caleb Coffie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;csc6972@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Researcher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aaron Herting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;adh2380@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Slide-maker&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which Entity did your team choose to profile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flattr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the Organization?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flattr is a Sweden-based microdonation provider founded by Peter Sunde and Linus Olsson and launched in March 2010. (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flattr" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flattr&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the project?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2010 Flattr launched via an invitation-only basis and then opened to the public on 12 August of the same year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flattr is a project started by Peter Sunde and Linus Olsson. Users are able to pay a small amount every month (minimum 2 euros) and then click Flattr buttons on sites to share the money they paid among those sites, comparable to an Internet tip jar. (The word "flattr" is used as a verb, to indicate payments through the Flattr system-so when a user clicks a Flattr button and they are logged in to the Flattr site, they are said to be "flattring" the page they are on.) Sunde said, "We want to encourage people to share money as well as content."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the service, Flattr itself takes 10% of all the users' monthly flatrate, although this fee may be reduced at a later date if the economics permit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2010, Flattr received large-scale attention when it was tweeted to be a method of donating money to WikiLeaks, which had recently been cut off by PayPal, Visa, and MasterCard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 28 April 2011, Flattr announced by email that they would not require users to flattr others before they could be flattrd themselves, starting from 1 May 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 16 April 2013, Twitter announced that they would no longer allow Flattr users to Flattr favorites citing commercial confusion problems they believed would occur between users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flattr#History" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flattr#History&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Describe each team member's role?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt Winters (Lead Writer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caleb Coffie (Lead Researcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aaron Herting (Lead Slide-maker)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization/Project Source Code Repository URL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/flattr" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/flattr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the easy parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flattr has been around for a while, and has a decently sized userbase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the hard parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It isn't terribly specific to open source, so writing the profile will require some creativity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The part after this is still the same as other teamprops...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How will you overcome both?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to overcome the large hurdles will be to just keep going with the work. Over time many of the confusing parts should be cleared up. We can also contact fellow classmates if we have problems and they might be able to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If something goes wrong, what contingencies do you have in place?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that I think might go wrong is a lack of information. To overcome this we can attempt to make contact with those involved in the projects and see if they're able to shed some light on the remaining information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When will your group meet regularly outside of class time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:30 AM Tues / Thurs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 9</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-9.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-05T12:53:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-05:foscis-week-9.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/foucault/" target="_blank"&gt;Michel Foucault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/Gustafson/FILM%20162.W10/readings/foucault.author.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;"What is an author?"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/Gustafson/FILM%20162.W10/readings/foucault.author.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/Gustafson/FILM%20162.W10/readings/foucault.author.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1969&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is another philosophical paper about authors and authorship. It discusses the various forms an author can take, and the various transitions "authorship" has made throughout history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would be way more interested in "complete works" collections if it included laundry bills. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The footnotes are nice. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The distinctive contribution of these authors is that they produced not only their own work, but the possibility and the rules of formation of other texts."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two sentences in, and I'm already writing something in this section. The "author" is not really an open question. It's the person who wrote (assuming this is strictly a literary context) a thing. That's it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Neither Hermes not[nor?] Hippocrates"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What are the modes of existence of this discourse?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perhaps this made more sense in the "real" class, but these past couple readings have felt wildly out of place. Why were they included?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happened to the annotations in the margins? Did the person annotating also get bored and subsequently distracted?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't "get" philosophy. This entire document seems like a crazy guy trying to redefine and bend the meaning of words, seemingly for the hell of it. I just don't see why any of it matters. Why would anyone care about this? "an anonymous poster attached to a wall may have a writer, but he cannot be an author." I mean, if you say so, man. It just seems pretentious and "intellectual" for its own sake. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile2 - Presentation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile2-presentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T17:39:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-02:profile2-presentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The slide deck for Profile2 is available &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1dpEAGEAahOXI4qd5ewZI_TNgqlzRd6OxB-a24Xw133U/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile2 - Arduino</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile2-arduino.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T17:31:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-04-02:profile2-arduino.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Rationale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arduino has a huge influence on the maker community. This community is very open to FOSS. The team was wanting just learn more about Arduino and the the relationship between Atmel and Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organizational Details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the subject of your profile a corporate entity?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What type?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corporation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When was it founded?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1984&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By whom?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Perlegos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original founder(s) still active?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No, he was actually fired. (&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2006/08/11/business/11norris.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2006/08/11/business/11norris.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publicly Traded? Since when? Initial Stock Price? Current stock price?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, since 1991. Started at 13.50, currently 8.53 as of 2015-03-18. (&lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/q/hp?s=ATML&amp;amp;d=2&amp;amp;e=18&amp;amp;f=2015&amp;amp;g=d&amp;amp;a=2&amp;amp;b=19&amp;amp;c=1991&amp;amp;z=66&amp;amp;y=6006" target="_blank"&gt;https://finance.yahoo.com/q/hp?s=ATML&amp;amp;d=2&amp;amp;e=18&amp;amp;f=2015&amp;amp;g=d&amp;amp;a=2&amp;amp;b=19&amp;amp;c=1991&amp;amp;z=66&amp;amp;y=6006&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any acquisitions? If yes, which companies, and what were their core products?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantum Research Group Ltd. (Capacitive Sensing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Digital Design S.A (Power line communication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smart metering product lines of IDT Corporation (Metering)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newport Media (IoT)
        (&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel#Acquisitions" target="_blank"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel#Acquisitions&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any investments in other companies? If yes, which ones.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not that I can find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Employees?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is HQ?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Jose, CA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it have any other offices or locations?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.atmel.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.atmel.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your organization file any annual reports? Please include links to any relevant documents (i.e. 990, Annual Report, Year in Review, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, they are all conveniently organized here: &lt;a href="http://ir.atmel.com/annuals.cfm" target="_blank"&gt;http://ir.atmel.com/annuals.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject participate in social media? If yes, please list a URL for each account, and reach within that community. (i.e. Twitter: @RedHatNews - 61.9K Followers.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atmel:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: @Atmel - 32.3K followers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn: 29K followers (&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/atmel-corporation" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/company/atmel-corporation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: @arduino - 125K followers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What communication channels does your subject use to reach their public? Briefly describe and include a URL for each.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since Atmel is a gigantic corporation, this doesn’t cleanly apply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They do have a blog: &lt;a href="http://blog.atmel.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://blog.atmel.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject organize or participate in any conferences? If so, list them here, and provide links to any relevant sessions, keynotes, or content.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atmel has a nicely organized list of past conference appearances: &lt;a href="http://ir.atmel.com/events.cfm" target="_blank"&gt;http://ir.atmel.com/events.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arudino organizes an Arudino Day: &lt;a href="https://day.arduino.cc/" target="_blank"&gt;https://day.arduino.cc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your subject likely runs or contributes to one or more Open Source products or projects. Choose one (or more) of these and answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If applicable, list and provide links to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project's IRC Channel&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#arduino on freenode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Code repository&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/arduino/Arduino" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail list archive&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/a/arduino.cc/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/developers" target="_blank"&gt;https://groups.google.com/a/arduino.cc/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arduino.cc/en/Main/Documentation" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.arduino.cc/en/Main/Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other communication channels&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forums: &lt;a href="http://forum.arduino.cc/" target="_blank"&gt;http://forum.arduino.cc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Website and/or Blog&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arduino.cc/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.arduino.cc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the software project, its purpose and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino - Create an easy to use open hardware made for makers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give brief history of the project. When was the Initial Commit? The latest commit?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial commit: Thu Aug 25 21:06:28 2005 +0000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Latest commit: Likely within 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who approves patches? How many people?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino - Many people approve patches on their github repo. At first glance it looks like there are 15 people who can merge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who has commit access, or has had patches accepted? How many total?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 15 have commit access and it there are currently over 400 pull requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has there been any turnover in the Core Team? (i.e. has the top 20% of contributors stayed the same over time? If not, how has it changed?)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems many of the contributors only contribute for a short period of time. There are only a couple people who have continually contributed. &lt;a href="https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/graphs/contributors" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have a BDFL, or Lead Developer? (BDFL == Benevolent Dictator for Life)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No there have been many people with commit access access and many of the developers have contributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the front and back end developers the same people? What is the proportion of each?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have been some of the major bugs/problems/issues that have arisen during development? Who is responsible for quality control and bug repair?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://forum.arduino.cc/?board=56.0" target="_blank"&gt;http://forum.arduino.cc/?board=56.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the project's participation trending and why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is increasing slowly. &lt;a href="https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/graphs/contributors" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, does the project pass "The Raptor Test?" (i.e. Would the project survive if the BDFL, or most active contributor were eaten by a Velociraptor?) Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes I believe it would survive because there are others that are actively contributing to the project and know their way around the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, would the project survive if the core team, or most active 20% of contributors, were hit by a bus? Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would probably survive but would take a while to recover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have an official "on-boarding" process in place? (new contributor guides, quickstarts, communication leads who focus specifically on newbies, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the software there are plenty of guides.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re looking to contribute to the project I can’t seem to find anything besides their Contributor License Agreement (&lt;a href="http://arduino.cc/en/Main/ContributorLicenseAgreement" target="_blank"&gt;http://arduino.cc/en/Main/ContributorLicenseAgreement&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have Documentation available? Is it extensive? Does it include code examples?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes Tons. It’s everywhere on their official site and even on the 3rd party sites explaining how to use arduinos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you were going to contribute to this project, but ran into trouble or hit blockers, who would you contact, and how?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably the IRC channel. #arduino on freenode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on these answers, how would you describe the decision making structure/process of this group? Is it hierarchical, consensus building, ruled by a small group, barely contained chaos, or ruled by a single or pair of individuals?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems like the project is ruled by a small group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the kind of structure you would enjoy working in? Why, or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah I believe they do a good job with structure and are continually on top of pull requests and issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology/Product (Section adapted from EFF Worksheet)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who invented, created, or sponsored the technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the technology designed to do? How is it used?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use microcontrollers. Many Makers use the microcontrollers for various different projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who would benefit from using this technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone trying to break in using hardware in a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kinds of companies or organizations (stakeholders) might have been concerned about the development of this technology? Why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Startups or companies with small teams that need to prototype hardware projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does/Did an aspect of copyright law play a role in controversies about the technology? How?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copyright plays a part with it being open hardware. They open the code up to anyone to use on their own boards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Litreview9</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/litreview9.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-31T10:21:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-31:litreview9.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mtu.edu/ece/department/faculty/full-time/pearce/" target="_blank"&gt;Joshua M. Pearce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Quantifying the Value of Open Source Hardware Development"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scirp.org/Journal/PaperInformation.aspx?PaperID=53076" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.scirp.org/Journal/PaperInformation.aspx?PaperID=53076&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Received 25 November 2014; revised 15 December 2014; accepted 25 December 2014"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This paper creates(?) three different metrics for evaluating the cost/time saving potential of open source hardware, and then presents a case study illustrating the cost/time saving ability of open source hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOSH is a really silly sounding acronym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is exhaustively sourced (which I guess is normal for academic papers), but if you have been following these litreviews (and if you aren't Remy, why would you be), you know I like citations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"electrospinning novel materials" is a fantastic phrase, even if it has &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; limited applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Creative Commons is technically a proper noun? The first paragraph has it lowercase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"open-source syringe pump (OSSP)" I'm not sure that really deserves its own acronym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"ranged from over $64,000 to over $1,000,000 for P = 1" Well, that's not a terribly specific range, is it? That's more of a guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wouldn't a whole bunch of designers be out of jobs if open source hardware took off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If an important open source medical device fails and someone dies, where does the liability fall?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the range of potential savings is so wide, can you really deem this "successfully provid[ing] three methods of quantifying the value of free and open source hardware"?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a well written, well organized paper. It provides clear examples, and is (relatively) easy to follow. However, I have difficulty comprehending the vast ranges of potential savings he presents - I know there is some guess work to be done, but a range of $1,000,000 is nothing to sneeze at. I suppose I've never done anything like this, so a million may in fact be a very small range, but I wouldn't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile0 - Presentation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile0-presentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-31T10:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-31:profile0-presentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The slide deck for Profile0 is available &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1z5I552woVkzGxhhwP1jXQHnIud8PJCvWaNJd34ZiBTI/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile1 - Presentation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile1-presentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-31T10:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-31:profile1-presentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The slide deck for Profile1 is available &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/14BSLcv87VmK7A5TotIrx1BnxcS7rk5wCIwLK-BUyh_o/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This clearly deserves its own post, because it is a different topic entirely. It is not &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt; a cheap way to boost my post count, in a bizzaro grading system where quantity actually is more important than quality. Weird!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 8</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-8.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-29T15:04:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-29:foscis-week-8.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This time, it's a full length movie film! And 4 pages of book scans! It still doesn't make sense, slightly delayed because of this Github DDoS, it's week 8 of FOSCIS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_Barthes" target="_blank"&gt;Roland Barthes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brett_Gaylor" target="_blank"&gt;Brett Gaylor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Death of the Author"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RiP: A Remix Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/Gustafson/FILM%20162.W10/readings/barthes.death.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://artsites.ucsc.edu/faculty/Gustafson/FILM%20162.W10/readings/barthes.death.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/17822690" target="_blank"&gt;https://vimeo.com/17822690&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1968 for "The Death of the Author"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2009 for &lt;em&gt;RiP: A Remix Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Death" is a wildly incomprehensible essay about, as far as I can tell, how masterpieces of writing are those which the author is "dead" - his or her views and biases cease to exist inside the written work. Or something like that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RiP&lt;/em&gt; is (yet another) film about remix culture, copyright / fair use law, and everything in between.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holy crap, that fake Disneyland in China is incredible. Apparently, there is an official Disney park opening &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shanghai_Disney_Resort" target="_blank"&gt;quite soon&lt;/a&gt;. (It's also confusing, as the text and spoken language was Japanese, but the video claims the park was in China. I assume that to be true, but still strange.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was not aware of Brazil's significant remix culture. How cool is it that their former Minister of Culture was also an active musician?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I actually stumbled across scans of Air Pirate comics &lt;em&gt;ages&lt;/em&gt; ago, and had no idea about the backstory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not sure what the best b-roll choice is when you want to play and focus on music, but having a tenth of your movie be people dancing is perhaps a bit redundant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of redundant, after having watched &lt;a href="http://everythingisaremix.info/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for BizLeg a few months back, this was more of the same, but better executed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good &lt;em&gt;God&lt;/em&gt; is "Death" unreadable. This is becoming an alarming trend with these sloppily-scanned PDFs. I can't critique it very much, as that would require thorough understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There seems to be a number of vocal critics, but is change even possible given the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;vast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; amounts of money that copyright lobbying groups have?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why was opensourcecinema.org shut down? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were any revisions or derivative works created based on &lt;em&gt;RiP&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I quite enjoyed &lt;em&gt;RiP&lt;/em&gt;, despite the fact that a good portion of it was preaching to the choir. I learned about some figures and areas of remix / open culture I didn't previously know about, and got to watch people dancing for a disproportionate amount of time! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As for "Death", well, you know. I guess I'm just not on a high enough arcane plane to comprehend it...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile1 - Apache Software Foundation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile1-apache-software-foundation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-19T18:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-19:profile1-apache-software-foundation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Rationale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had heard of the Apache Software Foundation before just never really knew too much about it. So we just wanted to look into it more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organizational Details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the subject of your profile a corporate entity?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What type?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Apache Software Foundation is a 501(c)(3) non-profit corporation. (http://www.apache.org/foundation/)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When was it founded?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They were incorporated in 1999.(&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apache.org/foundation/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By whom?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brian Behlendorf, Ken Coar, Mark Cox, Lars Eilebrecht, Ralf S. Engelschall, Roy T. Fielding, Dean Gaudet, Ben Hyde, Jim Jagielski, Alexei Kosut, Martin Kraemer, Ben Laurie, Doug MacEachern, Aram Mirzadeh, Sameer Parekh, Cliff Skolnick, Marc Slemko, William (Bill) Stoddard, Paul Sutton, Randy Terbush, Dirk-Willem van Gulik (&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation" target="_blank"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original founder(s) still active?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of them are still active but not all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publicly Traded? Since when? Initial Stock Price? Current stock price?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any acquisitions? If yes, which companies, and what were their core products?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not so much acquisitions but they have funded many projects. Too many to list here. Look here &lt;a href="https://projects.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://projects.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any investments in other companies? If yes, which ones.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kind of… https://projects.apache.org/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Employees?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No employees but many volunteers (As many as 2663 volunteers &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation" target="_blank"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is HQ?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forest Hill, Maryland &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it have any other offices or locations?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internet? (&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation" target="_blank"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your organization file any annual reports? Please include links to any relevant documents (i.e. 990, Annual Report, Year in Review, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://apache.org/foundation/news.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://apache.org/foundation/news.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject participate in social media? If yes, please list a URL for each account, and reach within that community. (i.e. Twitter: @RedHatNews - 6- 9K Followers.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: @theasf - 27.5K followers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Apache/6538157161" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Apache/6538157161&lt;/a&gt; - Seems dead, no updates since 2010, 17K likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What communication channels does your subject use to reach their public? Briefly describe and include a URL for each.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the ASF is more of an oversight body, communications are generally done on a project level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject organize or participate in any conferences? If so, list them here, and provide links to any relevant sessions, keynotes, or content.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They organize Apachecon, and have since 2000. &lt;a href="http://apachecon.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://apachecon.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your subject likely runs or contributes to one or more Open Source products or projects. Choose one (or more) of these and answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If applicable, list and provide links to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project's IRC Channel&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#apache on freenode (&lt;a href="https://wiki.apache.org/general/IRC" target="_blank"&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/general/IRC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Code repository&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://svn.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://svn.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail list archive&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/foundation/mailinglists.html" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apache.org/foundation/mailinglists.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.apache.org/general/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/general/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other communication channels&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogs.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://blogs.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Website and/or Blog&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the software project, its purpose and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The Apache Software Foundation provides support for the Apache community of open-source software projects, which provide software products for the public good.” (&lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give brief history of the project. When was the Initial Commit? The latest commit?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who approves patches? How many people?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a fantastically large list of commiters organized by project: &lt;a href="https://people.apache.org/committers-by-project" target="_blank"&gt;https://people.apache.org/committers-by-project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who has commit access, or has had patches accepted? How many total?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 4,253 people listed on the commiters page. (&lt;a href="https://people.apache.org/committer-index.html" target="_blank"&gt;https://people.apache.org/committer-index.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has there been any turnover in the Core Team? (i.e. has the top 20% of contributors stayed the same over time? If not, how has it changed?)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A. The Apache Software Foundation has an elected board of directors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have a BDFL, or Lead Developer? (BDFL == Benevolent Dictator for Life)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the front and back end developers the same people? What is the proportion of each?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have been some of the major bugs/problems/issues that have arisen during development? Who is responsible for quality control and bug repair?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N/A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the project's participation trending and why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Up, the number of current members is quite large. It may be that they don’t demote users for inactivity, so it is a false sense of growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, does the project pass "The Raptor Test?" (i.e. Would the project survive if the BDFL, or most active contributor were eaten by a Velociraptor?) Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, the foundation is mainly run by the community so many people would be able step and take over the role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, would the project survive if the core team, or most active 20% of contributors, were hit by a bus? Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes. The Apache Software Foundation board of directors is elected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have an official "on-boarding" process in place? (new contributor guides, quickstarts, communication leads who focus specifically on newbies, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a “Get Involved” landing page that directs users to further information: &lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/foundation/getinvolved.html" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apache.org/foundation/getinvolved.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have Documentation available? Is it extensive? Does it include code examples?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ASF has a “top-level” wiki. “This General Wiki is a top-level overview of other wikis at the Apache Software Foundation, as well as overall Foundation-level information, at the bottom of this page.” (&lt;a href="https://wiki.apache.org/general/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/general/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you were going to contribute to this project, but ran into trouble or hit blockers, who would you contact, and how?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IRC would likely be the first place to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on these answers, how would you describe the decision making structure/process of this group? Is it hierarchical, consensus building, ruled by a small group, barely contained chaos, or ruled by a single or pair of individuals?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consensus building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the kind of structure you would enjoy working in? Why, or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ASF has extensive documentation and guides to getting started on any of the numerous projects it oversees - it seems inviting and friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology/Product (Section adapted from &lt;a href="http://www.teachingcopyright.org/handout/technology-history-worksheet" target="_blank"&gt;EFF Worksheet&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who invented, created, or sponsored the technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Apache Foundation is funding many different projects from donations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the technology designed to do? How is it used?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide a foundation for open, collaborative software development projects by supplying hardware, communication, and business infrastructure;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create an independent legal entity to which companies and individuals can donate resources and be assured that those resources will be used for the public benefit;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide a means for individual volunteers to be sheltered from legal suits directed at the Foundation's projects; and,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protect the 'Apache' brand, as applied to its software products, from being abused by other organizations.
(&lt;a href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/faq.html#why" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apache.org/foundation/faq.html#why&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who would benefit from using this technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Source Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kinds of companies or organizations (stakeholders) might have been concerned about the development of this technology? Why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The open source community and companies that use Apache licensed software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does/Did an aspect of copyright law play a role in controversies about the technology? How?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Teamprop2</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/teamprop2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-18T14:47:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-18:teamprop2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Team Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Email&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caleb Coffie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;csc6972@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Researcher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which Entity did your team choose to profile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmel / Arudino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the Organization?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmel Corporation is an American-based designer and manufacturer of semiconductors, founded in 1984. The company focuses on embedded systems built around microcontrollers. Its products include microcontrollers (8-bit AVR, 32-bit AVR, ARM-based, automotive grade, and Intel 8051 derivatives) radio frequency (RF) devices including Wi-Fi, EEPROM, and flash memory devices, symmetric and asymmetric security chips, touch sensors and controllers, and application-specific products. Atmel supplies its devices as standard products, application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs), or application-specific standard product (ASSPs) depending on the requirements of its customers. (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmel&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the project?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arduino is an open-source computer hardware and software company, project and user community that designs and manufactures kits for building digital devices and interactive objects that can sense and control the physical world.Arduino boards may be purchased preassembled, or as do-it-yourself kits; at the same time, the hardware design information is available for those who would like to assemble an Arduino from scratch. (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arduino" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arduino&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Describe each team member's role?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt Winters (Lead Writer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caleb Coffie (Lead Researcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization/Project Source Code Repository URL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/arduino/Arduino" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;List your upstream Mentor's below:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have submitted a PR to remove this section from the template, since it doesn't really apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the easy parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino has a massive community, so I imagine finding information about it will be quite easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the hard parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because it is such an open-ended project, it may be difficult to find specific information about business-side of Arudino.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The part after this is still the same as teamprop0 and teamprop1...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How will you overcome both?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to overcome the large hurdles will be to just keep going with the work. Over time many of the confusing parts should be cleared up. We can also contact fellow classmates if we have problems and they might be able to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If something goes wrong, what contingencies do you have in place?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that I think might go wrong is a lack of information. To overcome this we can attempt to make contact with those involved in the projects and see if they're able to shed some light on the remaining information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When will your group meet regularly outside of class time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:30 AM Tues / Thurs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Litreview8</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/litreview8.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-18T13:57:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-18:litreview8.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean_Tirole" target="_blank"&gt;Jean Tirole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kva.se/globalassets/priser/ekonomi/2014/pop_ek_en_14.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;"Market power and regulation"&lt;/a&gt; (It's a little unclear who wrote this document, as I'm sure six pages isn't enough to warrant a Nobel prize. It is however a summation of Jean Tirole's ideas, so we'll credit him.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kva.se/globalassets/priser/ekonomi/2014/pop_ek_en_14.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.kva.se/globalassets/priser/ekonomi/2014/pop_ek_en_14.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PDF in question is a summation of a likely very dense economic paper. It covers Mr. Tirole's contributions to economic theory about oligopoly - where one market is controlled by a handful of very powerful companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That illustration on the first page is pretty spectacular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"mastering one link of a chain can allow a monopolist to make profits in the market of the next link."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Tirole’s research would come to build upon new scientific methods, particularly in game theory and contract theory." - There's such a thing as "contract theory"‽&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not sure whose fault this really is, but this is a very mysterious document. Who wrote it? Was it Mr. Tirole? If so, why is he writing in the third person? A little more background would be nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not entirely sure how this fits in with the course. Sure, it's business and all, but how does it relate to FOSS?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Even with a well-designed framework, a regulator will sometimes appear to be an advocate of the firm, but despite this she will nevertheless not allow herself to be bribed or actively withhold information." - This sentence is tremendously confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The idea of "asymmetric information" is a perplexing. If one is a regulatory body, couldn't you make laws and then demand whatever information you wanted?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The document mentions "a menu of ingeniously constructed contracts," and then goes on to discuss exactly two kinds. Are there more, or is it just a very short menu?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't spend a whole lot of time thinking about economics, but how did the concept of an oligopoly not exist in economic theory before Mr. Tirole's work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't feel particularly strongly about this document. It was mildly interesting, was well written, and conveyed information adequately. Beyond that, it is rather unremarkable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 7</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-7.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-15T12:09:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-15:foscis-week-7.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Oh, wow. Another reading about authorship. Weird. It's FOSCIS week 7!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.adrianjohns.com/about/" target="_blank"&gt;Adrian Johns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://english.dartmouth.edu/people/donald-e-pease" target="_blank"&gt;Donald E. Pease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://amitraydotnet.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/adrian_johns-piracy-ch-1and2.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piracy&lt;/em&gt; Chapters 1 + 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.westga.edu/~mmcfar/Author.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;"Author" from &lt;em&gt;Critical Terms for Literary Study&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://amitraydotnet.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/adrian_johns-piracy-ch-1and2.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://amitraydotnet.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/adrian_johns-piracy-ch-1and2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.westga.edu/~mmcfar/Author.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.westga.edu/~mmcfar/Author.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piracy&lt;/em&gt; has a copyright date of 2009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Author" has a copyright date of 1995&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gist&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piracy&lt;/em&gt; (chapters 1 and 2 at least) tells the tale of the origin of "piracy",
in the era of the printing press. Chapter 1 is an overview of the rest of
the book, as well as a handful of anecdotes about piracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Author" is a very dense philosophical article about the word "author", its
various uses and definitions, and how it they have changed over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Good&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had never heard the anecdote about the pirate version NEC. That's dedication
to a ruse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"has even outlawed the promulgation of algorithms that might be used to
disable or circumvent copy-protection" - I knew the DMCA was stupid, I didn't
know it was THAT stupid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a fan of etymology, it was interesting to read the &lt;em&gt;detailed&lt;/em&gt; history
of the word "author".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Bad&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Readers and commentators in the blogosphere reproduced the original press
 reports many times over." Yes, the blogosphere. That thing that still exists.
 (I know this is from 2009, but that still feels dated to use "blogosphere")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Author" is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; dense. I struggled to read it. I generally
don't have much difficulty with reading stuff (in English at least), but this
one was a challenge. I don't know if it was the scan, the font, or what; but
it was &lt;em&gt;physically&lt;/em&gt; difficult to read as well as academically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The utterly textual milieu of the poststructuralists is ruled by the critic,
or the authorless subject, as opposed to the author." If you say so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Questions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did robbery at sea turn into a term used for copyright infringement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why have territorial borders always played such a role in copyright? It
makes sense in older times when copying works was more difficult, but why
is it still such an issue today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does the future of piracy look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piracy&lt;/em&gt; is an interesting read, and I may end up picking up the full version.
It is readable (definitely more so than "Author"), and relatively engaging.
I can always nitpick some word choice or grammar usage, but it seems well
written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Author" is nigh unreadable. The jargon is packed so densely (as well as
the text itself!) that it is difficult to comprehend. I'm not a fan of
philosophy in general, and this did little to change my mind on the matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Profile0 - Wordpress</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/profile0-wordpress.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-12T17:57:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-12:profile0-wordpress.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Rationale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress is a gigantic thing. It powers (at least) 23% of the web. (&lt;a href="http://w3techs.com/technologies/details/cm-wordpress/all/all" target="_blank"&gt;http://w3techs.com/technologies/details/cm-wordpress/all/all&lt;/a&gt;) We wanted to dive deeper into what the community looks like that generates such a massively popular piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also one of the suggested ones, so that is also a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organizational Details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the subject of your profile a corporate entity?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automattic is the corporate entity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What type?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When was it founded?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 27, 2003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By whom?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mullenweg and Mike Little&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Original founder(s) still active?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mullenweg is still active on the project. Mike Little is no longer active on the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publicly Traded? Since when? Initial Stock Price? Current stock price?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automattic/Wordpress is not publically traded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any acquisitions? If yes, which companies, and what were their core products?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gravatar - Avatars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BuddyPress - Social networking on a blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IntenseDebate - Commenting service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polldaddy - Surveys and polls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blo.gs - Directory of blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After The Deadline - Spell checker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plinky - Writing prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code Garage - Backups and security scanning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simperium and Simplenote - Note taking and data synchronization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poster - Wordpress mobile app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean Domain Search - Domain name search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloudup - File-sharing service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longreads - Sharing service for long form posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll Kit - Visual HTML editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parka - Security scanning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code For the People - Wordpress development firm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source: &lt;a href="http://wptavern.com/a-look-back-at-16-automattic-acquisitions-since-2007" target="_blank"&gt;http://wptavern.com/a-look-back-at-16-automattic-acquisitions-since-2007&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the company made any investments in other companies? If yes, which ones.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No they have not. They normally just purchase the companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Employees?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;306 (&lt;a href="http://automattic.com/about/" target="_blank"&gt;http://automattic.com/about/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is HQ?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;132 Hawthorne St, San Francisco, CA 94107 (&lt;a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/automattic" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/automattic&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it have any other offices or locations?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://automattic.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://automattic.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automattic" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automattic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your organization file any annual reports? Please include links to any relevant documents (i.e. 990, Annual Report, Year in Review, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bi-annual transparency reports: &lt;a href="http://transparency.automattic.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://transparency.automattic.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject participate in social media? If yes, please list a URL for each account, and reach within that community. (i.e. Twitter: @RedHatNews - 61.9K Followers.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter: @wordpress - 442K followers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What communication channels does your subject use to reach their public? Briefly describe and include a URL for each.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users of the SaaS product can get notifications and other info on their landing pages. Users of their own installations can get similar notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Twitter handle mentioned above appears to be more or less a release log.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your subject organize or participate in any conferences? If so, list them here, and provide links to any relevant sessions, keynotes, or content.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordcamp - first organized by Matt Mullenweg, but numerous spinoffs have been established. &lt;a href="http://central.wordcamp.org/about/" target="_blank"&gt;http://central.wordcamp.org/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s a conference aggregator named Lanyrd that has a Wordpress tag: &lt;a href="http://lanyrd.com/topics/wordpress/" target="_blank"&gt;http://lanyrd.com/topics/wordpress/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Community Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your subject likely runs or contributes to one or more Open Source products or projects. Choose one (or more) of these and answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If applicable, list and provide links to:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project's IRC Channel&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/IRC" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/IRC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Code repository&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://core.svn.wordpress.org/trunk/" target="_blank"&gt;https://core.svn.wordpress.org/trunk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mail list archive&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/Mailing_Lists" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/Mailing_Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other communication channels&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are currently evaluating Slack: &lt;a href="https://make.wordpress.org/chat/" target="_blank"&gt;https://make.wordpress.org/chat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Website and/or Blog&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wordpress.org/news/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wordpress.org/news/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wordpress.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wordpress.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the software project, its purpose and goals.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress is a blogging platform and CMS. “...the mission of the WordPress open source project: to democratize publishing through Open Source, GPL software.” (&lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Policies" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Policies&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give brief history of the project. When was the Initial Commit? The latest commit?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First commit: Tue Apr 1 06:17:43 2003 +0000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably in the last 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who approves patches? How many people?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It appears that the people who approve patches and those who have commit access are the same group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who has commit access, or has had patches accepted? How many total?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 42 people in the log of the SVN, so most likely a number smaller than 42 (assuming some people have since retired from contributing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has there been any turnover in the Core Team? (i.e. has the top 20% of contributors stayed the same over time? If not, how has it changed?)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a list of “Developer Emeriti”, comprised of 10 people. (&lt;a href="https://wordpress.org/about/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wordpress.org/about/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have a BDFL, or Lead Developer? (BDFL == Benevolent Dictator for Life)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead Developers: (&lt;a href="https://wordpress.org/about/" target="_blank"&gt;https://wordpress.org/about/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helen Hou-Sandí&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dion Hulse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Jaquith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mullenweg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Nacin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Ozz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are the front and back end developers the same people? What is the proportion of each?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 4 people listed as “design”, so we will call them front end devs for our purposes. Discarding the non-differentiated “contributing developers”, that leaves a 4/6 split for frontend/backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have been some of the major bugs/problems/issues that have arisen during development? Who is responsible for quality control and bug repair?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vast majority of Wordpress vulns are a result of third-party plugins, and as such, do not fall under the umbrella of the core project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No major bugs / vulns in core Wordpress were highly publicized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the project's participation trending and why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project’s number of contributors is difficult to gauge accurately - because of the architecture of the community, a large number of contributions via patches get “filtered” through a smaller number of people. As such, the number of contributors has remained roughly the same over time. (&lt;a href="https://www.openhub.net/p/wordpress" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.openhub.net/p/wordpress&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, does the project pass "The Raptor Test?" (i.e. Would the project survive if the BDFL, or most active contributor were eaten by a Velociraptor?) Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, because there are numerous people with access to the main repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your opinion, would the project survive if the core team, or most active 20% of contributors, were hit by a bus? Why or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe not - the access to the main repo seems limited at best, and consequently the most active are the ones who have access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have an official "on-boarding" process in place? (new contributor guides, quickstarts, communication leads who focus specifically on newbies, etc...)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a Contributor Handbook, but it’s in a very rough state: &lt;a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/handbook/" target="_blank"&gt;https://make.wordpress.org/core/handbook/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the project have Documentation available? Is it extensive? Does it include code examples?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User documentation is at: &lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code documentation is at: &lt;a href="https://developer.wordpress.org/reference/" target="_blank"&gt;https://developer.wordpress.org/reference/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sets of documentation are extensive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you were going to contribute to this project, but ran into trouble or hit blockers, who would you contact, and how?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking in the Slack most likely, but it appears to be invite only / requires approval before accounts can be created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on these answers, how would you describe the decision making structure/process of this group? Is it hierarchical, consensus building, ruled by a small group, barely contained chaos, or ruled by a single or pair of individuals?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s a small group - one can only make changes with discrete patch files, not pull requests. Patches are submitted to the bug tracker (&lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://core.trac.wordpress.org/&lt;/a&gt;) and assessed / merged from there by core devs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the kind of structure you would enjoy working in? Why, or why not?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the strict structure resulted in a very robust and very stable core product, it feels difficult to contribute. It also feels a little too reliant on a small group of people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Technology/Product (Section adapted from &lt;a href="http://www.teachingcopyright.org/handout/technology-history-worksheet" target="_blank"&gt;EFF Worksheet&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who invented, created, or sponsored the technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Mullenweg and Mike Little founded Automattic Inc. to (initially) work on Wordpress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the technology designed to do? How was it used?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“...the mission of the WordPress open source project: to democratize publishing through Open Source, GPL software.” (&lt;a href="http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Policies" target="_blank"&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Policies&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a browser based CMS / blogging platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who would benefit from using this technology?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone who wants to publish content, written or otherwise, easily online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kinds of companies or organizations (stakeholders) might have been concerned about the development of this technology? Why?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers of other (commercial) blogging platforms, governments wishing to squelch dissent, and people who generally dislike blogs for whatever reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did an aspect of copyright law play a role in controversies about the technology? How?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A case of a fraudulent DMCA (fairly recent as well!): &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/9/8175491/wordpress-automattic-wins-dmca-takedown-straight-pride-uk-case" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/9/8175491/wordpress-automattic-wins-dmca-takedown-straight-pride-uk-case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting a FOSS minor when you are bad at coding</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/getting-a-foss-minor-when-you-are-bad-at-coding.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-11T16:37:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-11:getting-a-foss-minor-when-you-are-bad-at-coding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not good at coding. Well, that's perhaps not true. I &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I'm bad at
 coding. That's why I don't do it a whole lot. Of course, the only way to get
 better at something is to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; it, but it's difficult to get better when you
 don't actually know if you're doing anything wrong. My code &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; (eventually)
 sure, but if all my variables are constructed the wrong way and if you do anything
 unexpected it catches fire, that's not exactly great code, is it? I could go find
 resources and train myself to write better code and have better practices,
 but I can't really be bothered, since I don't write code all that often. It's
 a vicious cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, for some reason, I'm taking (more accurately finishing) this FOSS minor.
I don't regret it, as it has been super fun and educational, but it feels weird
when I do so little coding. I help FOSS projects where I can - filing bug reports
(I can read code just fine), writing documentation, and so forth. I still feel
like a "lesser" FOSS contributor. I suppose I would be perfectly happy doing
these "lesser" things on my own, but when doing them for a grade, it gets
a little frustrating  and weird. At the same time though, the FOSS minor classes have
made me feel more comfortable getting into FOSS stuff, code or no code, so I
suppose it is progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's my serious blog post for now. Now I have to either come up with a way
to crash the ofCourse instance with my RSS feed, find some more extra credit,
or, I guess, actually write some more compelling posts. That first one seems
enticing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Teamprop1</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/teamprop1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-11T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-11:teamprop1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I was unclear on this last time, but these are apparently written individually, not as a group. As such, here is my entirely unique Teamprop1 (except that bit at the end, which will probably be the same on all these, unless something drastically changes...):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Email&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caleb Coffie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;csc6972@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Researcher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which Entity did your team choose to profile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Software Foundation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the Organization?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apache Software Foundation /əˈpætʃiː/ (ASF) is an American non-profit corporation (classified as 501(c)(3) in the United States) to support Apache software projects, including the Apache HTTP Server. The ASF was formed from the Apache Group and incorporated in Delaware, U.S., in June 1999. (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation" target="_blank"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_Software_Foundation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the project?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apache projects are defined by collaborative consensus based processes, an open, pragmatic software license and a desire to create high quality software that leads the way in its field. (&lt;a href="https://www.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Describe each team member's role?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt Winters (Lead Writer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caleb Coffie (Lead Researcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization/Project Source Code Repository URL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/apache" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/apache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://git.apache.org/" target="_blank"&gt;http://git.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;List your upstream Mentor's below:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is held over from HFOSS / some other class, so I'll just say I'll go into #apache on freenode and ask questions there? (&lt;a href="https://wiki.apache.org/general/IRC" target="_blank"&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/general/IRC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the easy parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache has fantastically robust documentation for their software, so I assume (perhaps incorrectly) the same is true of their organizational documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the hard parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not all of the questions in the profile will be easy to answer, and may not apply directly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The part after this is still the same as teamprop0...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How will you overcome both?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to overcome the large hurdles will be to just keep going with the work. Over time many of the confusing parts should be cleared up. We can also contact fellow classmates if we have problems and they might be able to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If something goes wrong, what contingencies do you have in place?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that I think might go wrong is a lack of information. To overcome this we can attempt to make contact with those involved in the projects and see if they're able to shed some light on the remaining information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When will your group meet regularly outside of class time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:30 AM Tues / Thurs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 6</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-6.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-08T15:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-08:foscis-week-6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week's articles are about Net Neutrality. This is somewhat strange, since the FCC &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/2/26/8114265/fcc-ruling-net-neutrality-victory-internet-title-ii" target="_blank"&gt;already passed Title II&lt;/a&gt; a couple weeks ago. I suppose this is where taking this class as independent study sort of falls apart, but no matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these articles are relatively short, I'll combine them into one litreview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bogost.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ian Bogost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aprilaser" target="_blank"&gt;April Glaser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Do We Save When We Save the Internet?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Open Internet Is Essential to a Free Internet: Why Net Neutrality Should Matter To Everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Bogost's article is dated 2014-05-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is dated 2014-09-10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Bogost's article questions the value of net neutrality, the validity of the openness of the current internet, and the (perceived) negative effects of the internet on daily life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article takes a decidedly opposite stance, spelling out the numerous potential dangers of a non-neutral internet, and (as is typical of the EFF) a call to action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is well cited, and gives specific examples of adverse effects enabled by not having strong net neutrality laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I vehemently oppose almost all of the ideas presented in it, Mr. Bogost's article is quite well written. "The weight and heat of your smartphone in your pocket, silently whimpering for you, a glass and metal kitten with a small, fragile body."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Ms. Glaser's article: "This is a particular concern as more Internet providers expand into content production and distribution. Network discrimination could be used to herd users towards services the ISPs offer, like Verizon’s RedBox, rather than their competitors." - This was always one of the examples I gave when having to explain net neutrality to someone less technically-oriented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ian Bogost must be a profoundly unhappy man. He seems to have little hope, is dismissive, and wants to (apparently) let the internet burn. I feel like this article is largely dominated by emotion, and has immense leaps in logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He seems to think that because giants like Facebook and Twitter exist, that new players can't enter the field. As such, implementing laws that hold that door open (however narrow it may be) are pointless. Sure, you may think things are bad, but why would not at least try to keep things from getting worse? Why would you just give up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This seems to be a common thread in the (admittedly very small) selection of anti-net-neutrality / anti-anonymity articles I have read - the authors seem to think that social media services are mandatory! "Sitting in front of the television, you grasp your iPhone tight in your hand instead of your knitting or your whiskey or your rosary or your lover." I mean, you don't have to. You are more than welcome to pick up any of those other objects (or people, as the case may be).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"You boot a browser and it loads the Yahoo! homepage" - so &lt;em&gt;that's&lt;/em&gt; why this guy is so jaded by the internet. I would be too, if I had to look at Yahoo! every time I loaded my browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the FCC's Title II ruling "save" the internet, or are there still more steps to take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When do the new laws go into effect?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have there been any scientific studies on adverse effects / mental health implications of Mr. Bogost's so called "sins" that he outlines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got most of it out in the "the bad" section, but holy crap, I couldn't agree less with Mr. Bogost. I mean, yeah, there are some super awful parts of the internet, and that sucks. There are also super awful parts of the real world, and that also sucks. I'm not sure giving up on fixing the internet and letting it get monetized and corrupted into an unrecognizable nightmare is the best course of action. If someone's being a jerk, don't engage them, block them, and move on. The benefits of the internet (especially a neutral one) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; outweight the negatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bogost - -3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is much more to my liking, and not only because its ideas are much more in line with my own. It is less emotional (although there are still a handful of weasel words), and provides very clear, specific, and cited examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glaser - 4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Teamprop0</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/teamprop0.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-05T20:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-05:teamprop0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Team Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Email&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wyatt Winters&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;wxw7813@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Writer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caleb Coffie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;csc6972@rit.edu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lead Researcher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which Entity did your team choose to profile?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automattic/Wordpress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the Organization?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automattic, Inc. is a web development corporation founded in August 2005. It is most notable for WordPress.com (a free blogging service), as well as its contributions to WordPress (open source blogging software). The company's name plays on its founder's first name, Matt. (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automattic)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Description of the project?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress is a free and open-source blogging tool and a content management system (CMS) based on PHP and MySQL. Features include a plugin architecture and a template system. WordPress was used by more than 23.3% of the top 10 million websites as of January 2015. WordPress is the most popular blogging system in use on the Web, at more than 60 million websites. (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WordPress)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Describe each team member's role?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wyatt Winters (Lead Writer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caleb Coffie (Lead Researcher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization/Project Source Code Repository URL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/wordpress" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/wordpress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;List your upstream Mentor's below:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None as of yet. We still will need to make contact with someone on their Slack. Currently waiting for an Invite.
How will you communicate with them? (i.e. IRC Channel, Email Addresses, mail lists, issue trackers, etc...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack: https://wordpress.slack.com/
IRC(old): #wordpress @ freenode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the easy parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress is pretty gigantic, so information should be easy to come by.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you anticipate the hard parts will be?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're all making this up as we go, so the actual presentations / profiles are going to be weird the first couple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This form doesn't seem completely appropriate for making short-term presentation teams, so making up answers for these questions is difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How will you overcome both?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to overcome the large hurdles will be to just keep going with the work. Over time many of the confusing parts should be cleared up. We can also contact fellow classmates if we have problems and they might be able to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If something goes wrong, what contingencies do you have in place?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that I think might go wrong is a lack of information. To overcome this we can attempt to make contact with those involved in the projects and see if they're able to shed some light on the remaining information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When will your group meet regularly outside of class time?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:30 AM Tues / Thurs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Litreview7</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/litreview7.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-05T10:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-05:litreview7.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This litreview is about an article, and a paragraph in another article! Weird! It's Litreview7!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opensource.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Open Source Initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;copyleft.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open Source Case for Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Section 12.1, which is like a paragraph)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php" target="_blank"&gt;http://opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;http://copyleft.org/guide/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Open Source Case for Business&lt;/em&gt; was first indexed by archive.org &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20020624034017/http://www.opensource.org/advocacy/case_for_business.php" target="_blank"&gt;2002-06-24&lt;/a&gt;, so we'll call that the publish date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Copyleft Guide has copyright notices dated 2014, so the last revision was sometime then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open Source Case for Business&lt;/em&gt; outlines and explains the various benefits for business for getting involved in open source development. It also outlines the various business models that an open source business may use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Copyleft Guide (Section 12.1) notes that using GPL'd software in the enterprise is not only cheap (as in free), it's easy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've never heard the term "widget frosting," but I find it quite amusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The first bazaar project in a given niche is more likely to attract the best co-developers to invest time in it."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"If builders built houses the way programmers built programs, the first woodpecker to come along would destroy civilization."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"...high technology products (laptops, personal assistants, cellphones, etc)" Isn't there usually a "digital" in "personal [digital] assistant?" Even then, nobody actually talks about PDAs anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"In today's fast-moving, short-product-cycle business climate" &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BUZZWORDS!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Open-source authors frequently find themselves receving [sic], for free, port changes for operating systems and environments they barely know exist and can't afford developers to support." Perhaps this is just my lack of knowledge, but is this actually that frequent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you create software for sale, how does open source development work? People can just compile their own version. Do you just assume most people can't / are too lazy to do that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Using Free Software has a substantially lower cost of ownership" Isn't it free? Is that just strangely worded, or are there costs associated with free software I'm not thinking of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"In an independent head-to-head reliability test, open-source Unix systems and utilities were less fragile - crashed or hung less often - than their proprietary counterparts." Citation needed? You can't just say that without citing a source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found this article a little hyperbolic. It makes grand claims, some of which are backed up, some of which are unsubstantiated. In general, it provides a decent outlines of the benefits of open source for all businesses - those who already have a foot in the FOSS space, and those looking to make inroads into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>RITLUG 2015-02-27</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/ritlug-2015-02-27.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-04T13:27:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-04:ritlug-2015-02-27.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of bizlegfoss, we have to go to a FOSS related event or meetup at least once a month. Generally, this would be RocPy, but there was a misunderstanding on where the carpools would depart from, so I ended up missing February's meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead, I ended up going to RIT's own RIT Linux User's Group, or RITLUG. Apparently, I picked a rather off-week to show up. I showed up at the 4 PM, and it ended up being me and someone who I think was the president / leader / main person of the group? People continued to trickle in over the next 20 minutes, but no presentations or any formal meeting type stuff happened. I am confident it was the correct room, but apparently nobody had made a presentation to give that week, so it boiled down to me half-listening to a guy informally rant about systemd and parent/child process inheritance. I suppose that counts as the presentation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all rather unfortunate as this meeting was the only one I could actually carve out time in my schedule for. I'm sure the RITLUG meetings are fantastic when there are presentations, but I picked a dreadful week to go. I will definitely try to get to RocPy in March this time, and maybe give RITLUG a second chance later this semester.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Litreview6</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/litreview6.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-03T10:22:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-03:litreview6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's time to finish that FOSS primer, albeit a little out of order! Here's Litreview6:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter &lt;em&gt;3&lt;/em&gt; this time!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on the title page indicates version 1.5.2 was released 2008-06-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter covers organizational issues and obstacles, the various organizational structures that may be appropriate for a FOSS project, how to file taxes, and (hopefully) not get sued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I ever want to start a non-profit, I have a much better (if still rough) understanding of how to do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For being such a notoriously strict organization, I still find it hilarious that there are official IRS forms that end in "EZ."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like this chapter specifically does a decent job of going &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; deep enough on each topic to allow me to make better decisions on which organizational structures / forms to research further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The law offers no clear test for what amounts
to a substantial amount of legislative activities." Well, that's a bit of an oversight isn't it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For a chapter about organizational structures, it seems to go from "Well, you could be one of these" to "You're a 501(c)(3), here's what to do now" pretty quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really don't understand most of the section about directors. "They must promote the organization’s mission and avoid acting in self interest." Well, obviously? Why would one ever appoint a selfish, malicious director?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are "duty of care" and "duty of loyalty" actual legal terms, and do they really need to be defined? One would hope whoever you are making a director would already fulfill those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is starting a non-profit without legal counsel feasible (even if it's not advisable)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do things change when projects have developers from multiple countries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who doesn't plan on starting an organization any time soon (and will likely try and avoid it, as it sounds rather treacherous), this chapter wasn't terribly engaging. However, reading the sections about non-profits was educational - knowing that there is at least some level accountability is encouraging. Should the inescapable need to form a non-profit arise, I would have at least a better idea of things to discuss with legal counsel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 5</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-01T19:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-01:foscis-week-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two readings this week, so I guess I'll do a section for each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Removing Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/~hsdept/bios/galison.html" target="_blank"&gt;Peter Galison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Removing Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Autumn" 2004, based on the copyright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article discusses the ever-growing domain of the United States' classification of information, and (in no uncertain terms) the numerous downsides of that power creep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What is the level of damage (“damage,” “serious damage,” or “exceptionally grave damage”)..." That's a steep curve of clasification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Under the Atomic Energy Acts of 1946 and 1954... If I think of a new scheme for channeling X-rays from a fission primary to a thermonuclear secondary and write that idea down, I am (strictu sensu) forbidden from possessing the page I just created." I had no idea about those Acts. How did that make sense to include?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"We probably would not know if a national security secret was as well-kept as the secret of Coca-Cola"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand Dr. Galison has a PhD, but can we reign in the $400 words? I like to think I have a pretty decent vocabulary, but there were a number of words I had to look up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While being somewhat difficult to read, this was &lt;em&gt;not at all&lt;/em&gt; engaging. While Dr. Galison is clearly passionate about this issue, I don't feel particularly swayed by the article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"On the one side, an unaffordable, intractable, holist antiepistemology, on the other a ludicrously naive punctiform one." Well, time for a dictionary, huh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the classified document catalog is massive, what percentage of it is academically / politically / scientifically interesting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any progress on classification reform since this paper was written?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why does storing classified documents cost so much money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe it's because I'm not in the highest-tier of academics, or perhaps I just have other things to worry about, but the issue raised in this paper doesn't interest me at all. Sure, transparency is great and all, but I've found (again, this is probably because I'm not a high-tier academic) most government documents terribly uninteresting. Maybe there's just a certain age you hit and a biological switch fires and you suddenly get super interested in politics? I guess I haven't gotten there yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geeks, Social Imaginaries, and Recursive Publics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Christopher Kelty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geeks, Social Imaginaries, and Recursive Publics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2005, based on the copyright and filename.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This document (exhaustively) discusses the anthropologically unique "social imaginary" that is the internet, its users, and the malleability of both the protocols and the discussion topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Boston to Berlin to Bombay (Mumbai)" I love alliteration, even more so when it only accomplished through creative means. Good on you, Professor Kelty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That list of job titles is fantastic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"trying to take something off of the Internet is like trying to take pee out of a pool." I've never actually heard that one before. I'm well familiar with the concept, but never heard it articulated that way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not a fan of the terms "geek" or "nerd". I feel like they have been co-opted and subsequently bastardized by businessmen trying to ride the "hip new cool wave" of Doctor Who and The Avengers. Seeing it in an academic paper is similarly disgusting to me, however appropriate it may or may not be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"dot.com boom" - I'm not sure that's the standard syntax for that phenomenon...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This falls into a similar trap of the last document - the jargon (in this case anthropological) is so dense that readability for laymen such as myself is compromised. I suppose I'm not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; the intended audience for this document, but still.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would this paper be different if written today, if at all?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the uniqueness of the internet from an anthropological perspective be used to improve / further understanding of other societies / groups / [anthropological unit of people]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the internet still a subject of intense anthropological interest as it (apparently) was in 2005?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article was definitely more interesting than the last, but not by much. It may just be my cynical, reductionist approach to things, but it seems like the whole thesis of the paper is "People who like the same stuff get in groups to talk about it / make stuff; also, the internet is pretty cool, huh?" Perhaps I'm just jaded about the uniqueness of the internet because I have spent the majority of my life interacting with it. In addition, I've always been a little dismissive of cultural anthropology after I took a &lt;em&gt;startlingly&lt;/em&gt; boring course in it, and this article isn't terribly different. That list of job titles was pretty incredible though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Vidreview1</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/vidreview1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-26T10:27:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-26:vidreview1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The complexity and novelty of the titles has hit rock bottom. Oh well. Here's Vidreview1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karen_Sandler" target="_blank"&gt;Karen Sandler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/AllThingsOpen/trademarks-allthingsopen" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trademarks and Your Free and Open Source Software Project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JY6AtbtAuts" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JY6AtbtAuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-10-22&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This talk is quite similar to Chapter 5 of &lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (PDF), likely because it was (at least in part) written by the same person. It covers trademark, and how it applies and helps / hinders FOSS projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The anecdotes were humorous, and helped reinforce the main points of the talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like the use of a trademark policy was more clear in the video than the written
chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was on the fence / confused why a FOSS project needs to trademark things, but
the example about &lt;a href="http://evergreen-ils.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Evergreen&lt;/a&gt; gave a clear
use case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not specific to the talk, but some of the questions were too quiet, and the
slides were occasionally difficult to see. Luckily they were posted &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/AllThingsOpen/trademarks-allthingsopen" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the content was redundant to the chapter we &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORANGE SHIRT GUY STOP JIGGLING YOUR FOOT!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If common law trademarks can be enforced, what's the point of registering?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there downsides to trademarking / registering trademarks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you use a name frequently without the "™", can you "go back" and enforce
it if you start using the "™" with it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can't quite decide if this is a good reinforcement of the content of the reading, or
is just reduntant information with a smattering of funny stories. While I
did get good examples of the benefits of trademarking in FOSS projects, it
seems like the only real use is shutting down the distribution of malicious
 / backdoored versions of your software. Regardless, it was relatively entertaining, informative, and decently paced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSS Primer Chapter 5 - Trademarks</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foss-primer-chapter-5---trademarks.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-24T12:23:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-24:foss-primer-chapter-5---trademarks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Litreview5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter 5 this time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on the title page indicates version 1.5.2 was released 2008-06-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 5 covers trademarks (both common law and registered), and how they
apply to and are used by FOSS projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The term "genericide" is pretty fantastic. I was familiar with the concept,
 but never had a name attached to it. What fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a much more thorough understanding of "™" vs "®", and how each differ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The definition for class 9 trademarks is fantastic:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Scientific, nautical, surveying, photographic, cinematographic, optical, weighing, measuring, signalling [sic], checking (supervision), life-saving and teaching apparatus and instruments; apparatus and instruments for conducting, switching, transforming, accumulating, regulating or controlling electricity; apparatus for recording, transmission or reproduction of sound or images; magnetic data carriers, recording discs; compact discs, DVDs and other digital recording media; mechanisms for coin-operated apparatus; cash registers, calculating machines, data processing equipment, computers; computer software; fire-extinguishing apparatus." (&lt;a href="http://www.uspto.gov/trademark/trademark-updates-and-announcements/nice-agreement-tenth-edition-general-remarks-class" target="_blank"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; computers and fire-extinguishing equipment are
in the same category. Also worth noting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This Class includes, in particular: ... protractors;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there enough trademarks for brands of protractors being filed that this is necessary
to include?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The section on Cease and Desist letters seems oddly short. Granted, it is
difficult to give generic advice for such, but it seems like it should be
more verbose, given how frequent (and scary) C&amp;amp;Ds are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"use your trademark in a consistent and distinctive manner." I'm not writing
master, but this seems like a bad idea - both from a readability perspective,
and also from a not-seeming-like-a-self-important-weirdo perspective. If the
word in question is in &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; every time it's used, that seems off-putting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In my continuing train of being picky about grammar / spelling, "signaling"
is spelled wrong in the Class 9 description. In addition, there are &lt;em&gt;numerous&lt;/em&gt;
instances of British English: "jewellery," "colours," "tyres". What?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As most FOSS projects are global (or at least have global reach),
are United States trademarks enforceable in other countries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When is it worth the trouble to register one's common law trademark?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do trademark applications ever get rejected, and if so, for what reasons?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter was significantly more helpful than the last. I definitely
have a better understanding of trademarks, and I feel like I could register
and enforce one with relative ease, provided I actually had anything worth
trademarking. The more I read legal things, it all seems so murky and
case-by-case that it's amazing there's any consistency to any of it. What
a strange set of systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Social Media is Terrifying</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/social-media-is-terrifying.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-22T14:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-22:social-media-is-terrifying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week of independent study, another medium.com article. This week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dashes.com/anil/about.html" target="_blank"&gt;Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article discusses the post-internet concept of "public," and the numerous
issues surrounding "public" content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I absolutely &lt;em&gt;despise&lt;/em&gt; Gawker and their entire network of sites, so I'm
always glad to see them disparaged by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Facebook chart is terrifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author's end goal is noble, so I respect that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"any of us might throw in a hashtag to gather our thoughts". I never want to
meet anyone who does that. Ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I admit that Twitter and Facebook both have significant "anti-privacy
creep," this article seems to be written from the perspective that Twitter and
Facebook are mandatory. I acknowledge that the regular, average user of social
media is less technical than I; I would like to hope that people understand that
the entirety of their generated content is being indexed and monetized.
Sadly, I know that isn't the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This author apparently doesn't understand private messaging, or other
methods of communication besides Twitter and Facebook. There are a &lt;em&gt;vast&lt;/em&gt;
number of options for less-public communication on the internet, ranging from casual to
paranoid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that the legal system &lt;em&gt;enabled&lt;/em&gt; things like the NSA's dragnet, does
legal reform for privacy / public content issues seem viable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should social media companies be more explicit about their privacy settings
and / or their business models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this problem fixable, and if so, what would be some of the steps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like this article. A number of places in the article talk about consent and the
end user not being able to give it concerning their content. This is
fundamentally flawed - the user gives consent for whatever they post as soon
as they post it. While this may not be ideal, that is the
current state of the social media, and that is unlikely to change any time
soon. One's options are take the good with the bad, or simply don't use
social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that the wide variety of nastiness that can happen
online (swatting, doxxing, harassment, people sending pizzas) is deplorable,
there are also some positives to truly public content - educational value
(there have actually been some fascinating data aggregation projects),
and even the CDC &lt;a href="http://fcw.com/articles/2013/01/25/flu-social-media.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;tracking and predicting the flu&lt;/a&gt;. The internet, specifically social media is a terrifying beast,
but there are a number of cool things that come out of it. I don't think it's the
fault of the services themselves, but rather the small percentage of awful
people who use them for their own, malicious ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all scary, uncharted territory for both society and our legal system.
Who knows if (and how much) it has to get worse before it gets better, if it does at all.
At the end of the day, all of this is opt-in. If you can't deal with the
potential wretchedness that could rear its head, don't sign up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Software Patents, and Corporate Pledges</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/software-patents-and-corporate-pledges.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-19T10:37:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-19:software-patents-and-corporate-pledges.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing from last post, now we read pledges from a handful of companies to not be jerks about their patents, provided your potentially infringing code is open source! That's nice of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litreview4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com" target="_blank"&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com" target="_blank"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com" target="_blank"&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.redhat.com/legal/patent_policy.html" target="_blank"&gt;Red Hat Patent Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/ibm/licensing/patents/pledgedpatents.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;IBM Statement of Non-Assertion of Named Patents Against OSS&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google's &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge/pledge/" target="_blank"&gt;Open Patent Non-Assertion Pledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat Magazine's &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/magazine/001nov04/features/patents/" target="_blank"&gt;The Red Hat Patent Promise: Encouraging Innovation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.redhat.com/legal/patent_policy.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.redhat.com/legal/patent_policy.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/ibm/licensing/patents/pledgedpatents.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.ibm.com/ibm/licensing/patents/pledgedpatents.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge/pledge/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge/pledge/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/magazine/001nov04/features/patents/" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.redhat.com/magazine/001nov04/features/patents/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Hat's Patent Pledge: ~2001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google's Pledge: Archive.org's first scrape is &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130331033642/http://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge/pledge" target="_blank"&gt;2013-03-31&lt;/a&gt;, so somewhere around then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The magazine article: November 2004. The article also mentions IBM's pledge, so some form of it existed around then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each company's pledge is essentially: "If you have infringing code in a project
that is licensed under an approved license, we won't sue you." Google reserves
the right to terminate their pledge though...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Red Hat article has some explanation and comparisons / critiques about
the pledges as they stood in 2004. Since I haven't heard any huge stories
about open source projects getting sued over patents, I guess they all worked
out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBM apparently owns a patent for &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/patents/US6285777" target="_blank"&gt;"Internet assisted mail"&lt;/a&gt;. They actually "invented" &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;printing out emails&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and
physically mailing them to people. I almost want that to exist, just because
it's so absurd. In our impending dark cyberpunk dystopia, this may become a reality. I,
for one, am excited.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suppose this also means that I could implement this myself (as it's on their list of pledged patents), as long as I open source it...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the list of patents that Google and IBM won't assert for FOSS projects,
it's amazing software gets made at all. There's just a patent called "Web browser system" (US 5793964 A)? I guess it's good they allow FOSS projects to use that one. It makes you
wonder how IE exists... Maybe that's why IE is so terrible, they have to design
around this patent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something about Red Hat's use of "Really Big Companies" as a proper (pro?)noun is
pretty humorous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Google: "Google is therefore pledging the free use of certain of its patents".
I think they accidentally a word. That sure happens a lot in these fancy legal documents, when
one actually reads them. Weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's getting repetitive at this point, but even after a handful of weeks reading them,
legal documents are still incredibly bland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suppose it's to be expected, but the Red Hat article could basically just read:
"There are other patent pledges, but ours is easily the best for everyone."
Have some humility!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has any open source project (of any size) actually been sued over patent
infringement? If so, did they actually take it to court?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there other companies that have similar pledges?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is "Internet assisted mail" actually implemented anywhere in the world, or
is that just a "in case this ever happens, we're ready" sort of patent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's tempting to rate these documents highly, simply because of what they
(theoretically) enable, and I understand they have to be written a certain way
to be (again, theoretically) legally enforceable, but it's still overwhelmingly
dull. That balances out to a 3/5, yeah?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Software Patents Sure Are Weird</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/software-patents-sure-are-weird.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-17T11:19:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-17:software-patents-sure-are-weird.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Litreview3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter 4 this time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on the title page indicates version 1.5.2 was released 2008-06-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4 specifically covers software patents, and the various obstacles
(and generic advice on defenses) that software patents create for FOSS projects
and developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a much better understanding of why software patents are so hated -
they are confusing, and seem &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; for exploitation and other nastiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find that a legal organization (granted, in a general context) saying
"design around the obstacle patent" really humorous. That seems like a bad idea,
for a number of reasons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be incorrect, but I'm left with the impression that, if one wants
to put in the work, most patents can be invalidated (relatively) easily?
That's encouraging, I suppose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have difficulty understanding why this document was written. It seems like
every other paragraph is "consult legal counsel for specific needs" or similar.
Why wouldn't I just go to a lawyer to begin with? (S)he could probably tell
me all this information, perhaps more succinctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole section 4.3 "Becoming Aware of a Patent" seems really strange.
It (from what I understand) pretty much says "wait for them to come to you,
then get a lawyer". What?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This chapter was even less readable than the last two. I understand why
lawyers get paid so much - this is difficult to understand, and incredibly
boring!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given the (from what I can tell) significant outrage about the current state
of software patents, is there or has there been any attempts at adjusting the laws
concerning software patents?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of the patent troll cases I've heard of, why are patents granted to such
vague and generic software patents?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who the heck comes up with the time periods in our legal system? Maintenance
fees are due every 4.5 years? You can seek damages for infringements occurring
up to 6 years in the past? &lt;em&gt;Why those numbers?!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I did glean some useful knowledge from this chapter, I found most of it useless.
I feel like most sections were simply "you &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; do this, but you should
probably just talk to a lawyer". In addition, I'm not sure if I should be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt;
afraid of software patents, or &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; so since they seem easy to invalidate.
There was some solid content, but it was buried behind vast walls of legal
jargon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Software: Classification and Preservation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/software-classification-and-preservation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-15T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-15:software-classification-and-preservation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So begins (perhaps a little late into the semester) my adventures in independent study.
In order to finish my FOSS minor at RIT, I am doing an independent study adaptation of a pre-existing course. Because of scheduling conflicts, I cannot take it normally before I graduate, and this is the last requirement to finish out the minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing an independent study version of a class that is very much focused around
reading and group discussion is perhaps a bit suboptimal, but I have been tasked with
writing blog posts / reviews of the readings in lieu of group discussions. It will certainly be an adventure. So, here's the first one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkirschenbaum" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Kirschenbaum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article is the transcript of the opening address at the Library of Congress' &lt;a href="http://www.digitalpreservation.gov/meetings/ndiipp14.html" target="_blank"&gt;Digital Preservation 2014&lt;/a&gt; conference. The author addresses the complexities of software as a "thing", and the difficulties that those complexities introduce to the archival and preservation of software in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a fantastically organized and written piece of prose. I have never given too much thought about the various forms software can take, and, while some of the forms were perhaps a stretch, it was weird to think of software as "epigraphy". It's kind of strange / terrifying to contemplate all the places one's name or data appears on various computer / software systems throughout the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"... is content enough? What counts as context for all our digital content?" This is a pretty serious issue, especially with older software. Trying to play almost any older C64 / Atari 2600 game is nigh-impossible without the manual. Sure, you can dump ROMs and put them on a server without breaking a sweat, but without the associated manuals and documentation, they aren't nearly as useful or interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading this article made me remember to fire up my &lt;a href="http://www.archiveteam.org/index.php?title=ArchiveTeam_Warrior" target="_blank"&gt;ArchiveTeam Warrior&lt;/a&gt; which I hadn't in a while. I might as well put all this spare RIT bandwidth to good use!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That title is pretty bad. Granted, some of the titles I have come up with aren't fantastic, but jeeze. Honorary mention for "Preserving.exe". Yeesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These weren't the author's words, but Thomas Scoville's quote about code and jazz was excruciating. Maybe it's my distaste for jazz, or maybe I haven't been able to have code "flow" as Mr. Scoville describes, but that analogy seems like grasping at very distant straws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "software as clickwrap" section was so short that it seemed like an afterthought. Software distribution does seem to be going increasingly in that direction, so why not discuss it more thoroughly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is software preservation actually as difficult as it is made out to be in this article, or is just a manpower / volume issue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is software a "lesser priority" for the archival / preservation community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the DMCA or other copyright restrictions significantly hindered software archival efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who has been vaguely interested in software archival (and spent a fair amount of time browsing around Archive.org), this was a pretty interesting article. While I don't completely agree with everything presented, it was certainly thought provoking, and perhaps a little distressing. It's alarming to consider the future of all these server based products which likely will cease to exist in their current form at some point. A number of MMO games have disappeared, and can never be played again. It's weird to consider that possibility for a majority of the software tools I use every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Terms of Service documents are a pain to read</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/terms-of-service-documents-are-a-pain-to-read.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-12T09:05:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-12:terms-of-service-documents-are-a-pain-to-read.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I should probably stop including the class and week in the title. It is getting
a bit redundant at this point, huh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, here's the other assignment for this week, a triple threat of documents!
I even read something no man was ever meant to read, the iTunes TOS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assignment 2: "Litreview2"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://getfedora.org/" target="_blank"&gt;The Fedora Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/" target="_blank"&gt;The Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/us/terms.html" target="_blank"&gt;The iTunes Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Legal:Fedora_Project_Contributor_Agreement" target="_blank"&gt;The Fedora Project Contributors' Agreement&lt;/a&gt; (or the FPCA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://legacy.python.org/psf/contrib/contrib-form/contributor-agreement.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Python Software Foundation CLA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/us/terms.html" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.apple.com/legal/internet-services/itunes/us/terms.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Legal:Fedora_Project_Contributor_Agreement" target="_blank"&gt;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Legal:Fedora_Project_Contributor_Agreement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://legacy.python.org/psf/contrib/contrib-form/contributor-agreement.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;ttp://legacy.python.org/psf/contrib/contrib-form/contributor-agreement.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This iteration of the iTunes TOS was updated September 17, 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fedora Project Contributor Agreement is on a wiki (which doesn't allow
anonymous edits, so it's probably fine), and the last edit
was &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/w/index.php?title=Legal:Fedora_Project_Contributor_Agreement&amp;amp;oldid=402596" target="_blank"&gt;2015-02-03&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Python CLA doesn't indicate any obvious date/time information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iTunes TOS gets right to it in the first paragraph: "IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS, DO NOT CLICK "AGREE," AND DO NOT USE THE SERVICES."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fedora Project Contributor Agreement is in place to ensure that contributions
are assigned appropriate licenses as to not impede the progress of the project.
It is clear to point out that "The FPCA is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a copyright assignment agreement."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Python CLA is similar to the Fedora document, but significantly shorter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a somewhat well-known quote, but the iTunes TOS indicates: "You also agree that you will not use these products [iTunes and associated services] for any purposes prohibited by United States law, including, without limitation, the development, design, manufacture, or production of nuclear, missile, or chemical or biological weapons." You would &lt;em&gt;hope&lt;/em&gt; that you could omit the part after "purposes prohibited by United States law," but apparently
they felt it was necessary to include that. As with other warning signs, it makes you
assume that someone did that at one point, so they had to include it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The FPCA is significantly more readable (and more concise) than the iTunes TOS.
The sections are also zero-indexed, so that's fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Python CLA is an outlier in this group of documents - the entire thing
is roughly 2 paragraphs, but (I assume) still does the job to not cause any problems.
That being said, it is easily the most readable and non-lawyer friendly document of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iTunes TOS is &lt;em&gt;so long&lt;/em&gt;! I assume it's partly to cover every conceivable issue
(including biological weapons), but I imagine it's also partly so they can sneak in
nefarious things without being too noticeable. They also forgot / didn't type
a word here, under the heading "POPULAR NEAR ME":
"Apple will, from time to time, automatically collect information related to certain [aspects?] of your App Store Products."
I guess it's hard to proofread a 15790 word nightmare, but that's pretty obvious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's pretty nitpicky, but having the FAQ before the document that the FAQ is &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; seems
strange. In addition, I understand that it's for legal purposes, but the constant Use
of Frequent Capitalization on Defined Terms makes Reading it Pretty difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's hard to find flaws in a document as short as the Python CLA, but I suppose having
time / date information on the PDF would be helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I've heard conflicting things - are TOS and EULAs actually legally binding?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I still submit very small patches (typo fixes, etc) to Fedora without
signing / agreeing to the FPCA? Not that I'm opposed to it, but I'm lazy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have there been disputes that make contributor agreements necessary, or are they more
of a "if and when" sort of thing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewing legal documents seems weird. It's even more difficult because
I am not a lawyer, and I have no idea if they're any good. So, from that not-lawyer
position, these documents are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dreadfully boring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! While they vary in length
(iTunes obviously being the worst offender), they are written with so many
definitions and CamelCase words, they are nigh-unreadable most of the time.
The Python CLA is the most user-friendly document, but the link I was given
is on the subdomain legacy.python.org, so I'm guessing it was retired / updated
since this version was penned. I hope they didn't make it much longer...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>Further adventures in GPL land (BIZLEGFOSS Week 3)</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/further-adventures-in-gpl-land-bizlegfoss-week-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-10T10:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-10:further-adventures-in-gpl-land-bizlegfoss-week-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Assignment 1: "Litreview1"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;copyleft.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter 1 specifically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;http://copyleft.org/guide/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are copyright notices dated as late as 2014. So some time in 2014 was the last update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first chapter of this document explains various aspects of software freedom, such
as the GPL, copyleft ideology, and the differences between copyleft and public domain.
It is written in a (relatively) universally understandable way (meaning not
developer-specific).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, the in-PDF links are fantastic. Some are even to external sources!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"It was once rare that this freedom [the freedom to run] was restricted by even proprietary software; but such is quite common today."&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since most of my computing has been in the post-EULA era, this was interesting
to contemplate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I now have a way better understanding of software freedom vs. public domain software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Copyleft modifies, or 'hacks' copyright law..."&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more people use the term "hack" the less I like seeing it. It's been
muddied and overused, and doesn't really have a concrete meaning anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the wording feels a bit biased. It feels more like a persuasive document,
rather than a general-information document for people trying to learn more about
software freedom and the GPL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I love semantics as much as the next guy, it feels like their definitions of
similar terms are fuzzy at best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any downsides to licensing one's code under the GPL?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If one wants to make a living by writing code, is the GPL still viable / appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there cases where releasing into the public domain makes more sense than releasing
under the GPL?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While informative, this first chapter wasn't terribly interesting or engaging to read.
Regardless, it is undoubtedly well written, and exhaustively sourced. Given
the inherently dry nature of legal writing, it was more than adequate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>In which I read, watch, and write. (BIZLEGFOSS Week 2)</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/in-which-i-read-watch-and-write-bizlegfoss-week-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-04T13:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-04:in-which-i-read-watch-and-write-bizlegfoss-week-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having to write on this site this often is weird. I had gotten into such a deep
rut of assuming "oh, that's not really worthy of a blog post" about nearly
everything I do (so much so that I hadn't posted anything in like 15 months),
that having to write blog posts (for grades!) this frequently, on a variety of
topics, seems quite strange. Given how relatively surgical and calculated my previous posts have
been, this continues to be a foreign practice to me. Hopefully it will get more
comfortable (or I will stop irrationally worrying about every little thing that
I post. If I go for volume, maybe people won't see the occasional dumb thing I post!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the assignments for this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vidreview0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="#vidreview0"&gt;Assignment 1: "Vidreview0"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/remixeverything" target="_blank"&gt;Kirby Ferguson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingisaremix.info/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingisaremix.info/watch-the-series/" target="_blank"&gt;http://everythingisaremix.info/watch-the-series/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fourth and final part was released 2012-02-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a well done (and exhaustively sourced) documentary-of-sorts about
the history, impacts, and interactions between copyright, patent law, creative
culture, and (as the title would suggest) remixing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The production values were quite good, and it was obvious Mr. Ferguson put
a lot of effort into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm always a fan of not-actually-copyright-notice screens. This one wasn't
particularly funny, but still an excellent use of the trope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why, but the animated sequence at 9:25 at least on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=coGpmA4saEk" target="_blank"&gt;this copy&lt;/a&gt; was maybe my favorite part.
Very Sesame Street-esque.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Youtube version I was linked had some serious compression and artifacting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's common in these documentary / educational type pieces, but I don't
really like the "call to action" bit at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were points that just seemed over-produced - excessive transitions,
sequences with filters for no apparent reason, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The call to action part doesn't go far enough - what can one do to "fix" the issue(s)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While patent trolls are obviously bad, but what are the creator's opinion
about the current state of copyright length?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why was this video done in four parts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I actually enjoyed this quite a bit, despite some of the flaws noted above.
It was educational, engaging, and well made. However, it's difficult to understand
&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it was made, aside from being an educational piece. The creator obviously
feels strongly about the covered topics, but does nothing to encourage the viewer to
get involved in free/open source projects or really take any sort of action.
The ending felt more like it petered out than finished strong...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="litreview0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="#litreview0"&gt;Assignment 2: "Litreview0"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Intro to the end of Chapter 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on the title page indicates version 1.5.2 was released 2008-06-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a FOSS-developer targeted legal primer on a number of issues and
legal topics relevant to FOSS development. It covers copyright, licensing,
organizational structure, patents, and trademarks. It is intended to be a
guideline, not actual cut-and-dried legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links in PDFs are awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"If you find yourself feeling the urge to write a new license, it’s a
good sign that you might need to reconsider your approach."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had no idea about the Affero GPL, which seems like an excellent idea.
I wonder why it's not implemented more widely (or maybe I haven't been looking for it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"...send a letter, via as many different methods as possible (at least by email, courier service, and fax)." Fax? Really?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I understand the need, at points the concentration of acronyms got a little
unreadable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The section on copyright for documentation seems oddly short, especially after
they talk up the importance of good documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a simple(r) solution for small projects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this information globally relevant, or USA specific?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are there so many versions of the GPL, and what are the differences?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's hard to make legal guidelines / information exciting. I understand that.
I suppose this could be far less engaging, but given the nature of the material,
it was engaging enough. More than anything, I'm kind of terrified of FOSS licenses
and how they interact now. No wonder GPL violations (and other license violations)
are so common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>BIZLEGFOSS@RIT - Week 1</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-27T17:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-01-27:bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whoa, what? An update on this website that has been almost completely stagnant for over a year? Weird!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm somewhat hesitant to write a big long story giving exposition for why this post suddenly appeared, but since my Github account &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; bound to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/FOSSRIT" target="_blank"&gt;RIT FOSSBox's group page&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose it's not all that big of a secret where I go to school. If you're stalking me (or the NSA agent assigned to me) and didn't draw that conclusion, well, there you go, and also, you're bad at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, RIT is the first university in North America to offer &lt;a href="http://magic.rit.edu/foss/" target="_blank"&gt;a minor in Free and Open Source Software&lt;/a&gt;, and I get to be one of the first people to complete it! As such, I am taking "Legal/Business Aspects of FOSS", or BIZLEGFOSS for short (the short name apparently subject to change, but I rather like it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first homework assignment for this course was to make a handful of accounts (blog, github, freenode nickserv, etc), all of which I already had. The final part was to write a blog post about your experience. I could get a little recursive and write about writing this blog post, but that is both silly and time consuming. Hopefully this class will get me back into the blogging mindset. I do have a handful of topics to write about, so perhaps some of those will appear sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>NCL Fall 2013 Preseason</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/ncl-fall-2013-preseason.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-15T17:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-10-15:ncl-fall-2013-preseason.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week was the National Cyber League's preseason event, and my first formal CTF game. This is apparently to place the competitors into divisions for the "real" games. I finished 27th out of 518. I am not displeased with this result. The highest position I ever got to was 8th, but I fell significantly once the weekend hit (the event was a week long), and people had more time to dig into the flags. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some thoughts I had during the event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less password cracking. While password cracking is indeed a valuable skill, for CTF challenges (especially ones with tighter time frames, the real games are ~4 hours), it comes down to who has the best / most GPUs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor the targets (more). A large problem was the "Linux 1" target they had set up. The key to this one (spoilers!) was the &lt;a href="https://www.rapid7.com/db/modules/exploit/unix/ftp/vsftpd_234_backdoor"&gt;VSFTPD 2.3.4 backdoor&lt;/a&gt;. However, someone early in the week found this, opened the backdoor, and kept an active shell, preventing anyone else from getting in. This was eventually fixed on Thursday by adding a timer (by dropping the connection) to it. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track and punish saboteurs. Another target's trick was an unsecured phpmyadmin install with login of root and no password. Had I been feeling mean, I could easily drop all the tables, and wait for the admins to notice (and reset the target). This would prevent other players from getting the flags in that lag time. While I am well aware the difficulty of identifying wrongdoers and dangers of incorrectly punishing players, this is disappointing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't put flags on a Mediawiki install, unless you lock it down properly. I love Mediawiki, but an unmoderated wiki quickly falls into a war zone, as the Web 1 target exemplified. While it was easy enough to dig into the revision history, the target was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; slow from all the various attacks from the various users. I will admit that I enjoyed a message from the admins regarding this: "PS - Hitting the target repeatedly, with every automated tool you can think of, will likely not make the flags fall out." It turns out they were right. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the flag-entry less strict. This may seem greedy, but I feel that the software should be smart enough to ignore leading/trailing spaces that sometimes tag along when copying and pasting text. I also had a couple issues with upper/lowercase, something that I don't think should make that much of a difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I very much enjoyed the event, despite these hurdles. I understand that it is difficult to monitor and keep numerous boxes up when being hammered by 500+ people, especially when those boxes are &lt;strong&gt;designed&lt;/strong&gt; to be insecure. I applaud the admins for their diligence in resettings boxes, and I appreciate their assistance with getting my account configured (unique email addresses can sometimes break stuff!). I look forward to the proper games, but wanted to reflect on the preseason while I had some time. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Rubustat - the Raspberry Pi Thermostat</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/rubustat-the-raspberry-pi-thermostat.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-01T16:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-10-01:rubustat-the-raspberry-pi-thermostat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been some time since I actually wrote a blog post. Mostly because I have had nothing original to write, and partially because school keeps me busy. Let's change that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I would do a proper writeup on one of my summer projects - the Rubustat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I enjoy programming and enjoyed making this project immensely, I make no claims that I am good at programming. High level Pythoners may wish to look away. However, the only way to get better is practice, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at home for the summer, the existing thermostat in the house was acting up. It wouldn't keep programmed settings, the display was a cheap LCD that was losing contrast, and it was generally an annoyance. Having ordered a couple Pis earlier in the summer (because why not, it's a $40 computer!), I quickly began researching the potential of a Raspberry Pi thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Of course, someone already did it.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typically the case on the internet, someone had already implemented my idea, and was selling products. &lt;a href="http://makeatronics.blogspot.com"&gt;Nich Fugal&lt;/a&gt; had done exactly what I planned - &lt;a href="http://makeatronics.blogspot.com/2013/04/raspberry-pi-thermostat-hookups.html"&gt;hooked up an RPi to his thermostat&lt;/a&gt;. Handily enough, he offers the schematics and parts list he used! He also makes and &lt;a href="http://makeatronics.blogspot.com/2013/06/24v-ac-solid-state-relay-board.html"&gt;sells pre-made boards&lt;/a&gt; for easy solder-and-go purposes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I found his &lt;a href="http://makeatronics.blogspot.com/2013/04/thermostat-software.html"&gt;software&lt;/a&gt; implementation lacking, but admittedly functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/thumbnails/ubustat/rubustathookups_regular.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The controller board (left) and thermometer (right) crammed into the GPIO ribbon cable
&lt;br&gt;
I soldered the connector on the PCB backwards. Oops!
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Nich did most of the hard work hardware wise, I knew I could improve the software. While I am by no means a web developer, I am halfway handy with Python, and Flask fulfilled my purposes well enough. Let's go through my amateur-at-best design process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a huge fan of lazy portmanteaus, I knew it had to be something raspberry related. The genus of the common raspberry is Rubus, so the name "Rubustat" practically made itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The daemon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The daemon was originally based on a straight copy of Nich's &lt;a href="http://makeatronics.blogspot.com/2013/04/thermostat-software.html"&gt;software&lt;/a&gt;. However, I found it to be a tad unstable, and used more external bash calls than I liked. While his use of outdoor temperature to determine heating vs cooling is clever, the primary user of the end product (my dad) preferred more manual control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some extended debugging, I found that it was difficult to cleanly kill off my daemon (which at this point was a endless while loop). I instead opted to use a daemon class written by &lt;a href="http://www.jejik.com/articles/2007/02/a_simple_unix_linux_daemon_in_python/"&gt;Sander Marechal&lt;/a&gt; which worked better. To fully stabilize/debug the daemon, I had to add stale PID checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In it's final version, the daemon handles the GPIO pins, sqlite logging (initially to make fancy graphs, but the thermometer I ended up using wasn't precise enough to make any graphs except ones that look like sawteeth), email error reporting (implemented because one of the alligator clips fell off on the temporary hardware and the house got outstandingly warm), and monitoring of the status file to know what temperature and mode to be in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to learn the word "hysteresis", so that's fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The web UI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/thumbnails/ubustat/phoneui_regular.png" /&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Firefox for Android on a Galaxy Note&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/thumbnails/ubustat/desktopui_regular.png" /&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Firefox on Windows
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is primary reason the project was created. We could get any number of cheap, difficult-to-control thermostats, or we could get any of a slightly smaller number of expensive, web-enabled thermostats. The beauty of this project is we got a cheap, web-enabled thermostat! You don't have to learn how to program the schedules! I doesn't even have the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to run schedules! (feature forthcoming?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web UI looks like a hot pile of garbage. More importantly, however, is it a &lt;strong&gt;functional&lt;/strong&gt; hot pile of garbage. I don't have much exciting to say about this interface. It writes directly to the status file, which is in turn read by the daemon and adjusts the GPIO pins accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason the interface is so dang big is because I have no idea how to do reactive design, and the idea was for the UI to be mobile-friendly. In a very inelegant way, it is mobile-friendly. I did however implement &lt;a href="https://github.com/ftlabs/fastclick"&gt;fastclick&lt;/a&gt; so it feels like you're poking a button rather than a Slowbro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another in the line of features inspired by catastrophic failure is the daemon status section. I felt rather silly when the web UI started without the daemon, so the adjustments made would have no effect. While playing with this functionality, I included the GPIO statuses above that, the colors corresponding to the LEDs on the physical board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The wrap up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; security precautions in the code itself. If you make a Rubustat of your own &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DO NOT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; expose the RPi to the outside internet. It is a dreadful idea. It works just fine when confined to the LAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually pretty pleased with how this thing turned out. While it is by no means particularly pretty or elegant, it gets the job done, and doesn't catch fire. That's a success in my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to look over the source or run it yourself, hit the &lt;a href="https://github.com/wywin/Rubustat"&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Installing Tracks 2.2.2 on Debian Wheezy</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/installing-tracks-2-2-2-on-debian-wheezy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-30T10:59:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-07-30:installing-tracks-2-2-2-on-debian-wheezy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a chronicle of my first Ruby on Rails deployment, and the things I learned while doing so. It is likely straight-forward and obvious for Rails vets, but hopefully this will help people who just want to host and use the great tool that is &lt;a href="http://getontracks.org/"&gt;Tracks&lt;/a&gt; without too much hassle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assumed: apache2, mysql (you &lt;a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/blob/v2.2.2/doc/installation.textile#decide-on-a-database"&gt;can use sqlite3&lt;/a&gt; but I won't cover that here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;optional: php5, phpmyadmin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let's create a database and user for Tracks to use.
I used phpmyadmin here because its easiest for me, but you can do it as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;CREATE USER &amp;#39;tracks&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;***&amp;#39;;

GRANT USAGE ON * . * TO &amp;#39;tracks&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39; IDENTIFIED BY &amp;#39;***&amp;#39; WITH MAX_QUERIES_PER_HOUR 0 MAX_CONNECTIONS_PER_HOUR 0 MAX_UPDATES_PER_HOUR 0 MAX_USER_CONNECTIONS 0 ;

CREATE DATABASE IF NOT EXISTS `tracks` ;

GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON `tracks` . * TO &amp;#39;tracks&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39;;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Switch into a root shell with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo -s
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;for the remainder of the install process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need some packages, so let's install them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;apt-get install curl unzip libxslt-dev libxml2-dev libmysql-ruby libmysqlclient-dev libcurl4-openssl-dev apache2-threaded-dev libapr1-dev libaprutil1-dev
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Tracks works best with Ruby 1.9.3, so we will use Ruby Version Manager (RVM) to install it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;\curl -L https://get.rvm.io | bash
source /etc/profile.d/rvm.sh
rvm requirements
rvm install 1.9.3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Verify &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;which ruby
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;which gem
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;point to &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;/usr/local/rvm/rubies/ruby-1.9.3-p448/bin/ruby
/usr/local/rvm/rubies/ruby-1.9.3-p448/bin/gem
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;respectively, or something close to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have Ruby all situated, it's time to get Tracks.
In /root run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;wget https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/zipball/v2.2.2
mkdir /srv/tracks
unzip v2.2.2 -d /srv/tracks
cd /srv/tracks/TracksApp-tracks-bc8b817/
mv * ../
cd ..
rm -r TracksApp-tracks-bc8b817/
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now Tracks is unzipped and ready to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cd /srv/tracks
gem install bundler
bundle install
gem install passenger
/usr/local/rvm/gems/ruby-1.9.3-p448/bin/passenger-install-apache2-module
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The passenger install wizard will do its magic, and spit back out something similar to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;LoadModule passenger_module /usr/local/rvm/gems/ruby-1.9.3-p448/gems/passenger-4.0.10/buildout/apache2/mod_passenger.so
PassengerRoot /usr/local/rvm/gems/ruby-1.9.3-p448/gems/passenger-4.0.10
PassengerDefaultRuby /usr/local/rvm/wrappers/ruby-1.9.3-p448/ruby
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Append those lines along with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;PassengerDefaultUser www-data
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;to the end of /etc/apache2/apache2.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your VirtualHosts files (likely at /etc/apache2/sites-enabled/&lt;em&gt;yoursitehere&lt;/em&gt;), add&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;RailsBaseURI /tracks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;or whatever you want to be the directory that holds Tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Apache knows where to look, we need to tell Tracks what database to look for, and what settings to use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cd /srv/tracks/config
cp site.yml.tmpl site.yml
cp database.yml.tmpl database.yml
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Configure variables per &lt;a href="https://github.com/TracksApp/tracks/blob/v2.2.2/doc/installation.textile#configure-variables"&gt;official documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in /srv/tracks finish installation with the new database settings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;bundle exec rake db:migrate RAILS_ENV=production
bundle exec rake assets:precompile
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The final step is adding a link in /var/www to the public folder of Tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;ln -s /var/www/tracks /srv/tracks/public
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Restart Apache to make sure it's up to date:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;/etc/init.d/apache2 restart
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and point your browser to the Apache server.
If everything went well, you should be prompted with the admin account creation page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go get things done! &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Backwards-compatible Short URL conversion of Mediawiki</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/backwards-compatible-short-url-conversion-of-mediawiki.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-14T14:27:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-07-14:backwards-compatible-short-url-conversion-of-mediawiki.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Further adventures in mod_rewrite town! This time I had to convert a Mediawiki install to Short URLs while maintaining backwards compatability. Let's see how it went!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if you're like me, you don't plan ahead very much when doing software installs. A Mediawiki site I help with has been running for some time, and several links exist pointing to old, ugly URLs like "www.example.com/wiki/index.php/Main_Page". However, the decision makers wanted the links to lose the "index.php" in the URL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's easy enough to do. The &lt;a href="https://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:Short_URL"&gt;Mediawiki meta-wiki&lt;/a&gt; has a great write up on the topic. They also link to &lt;a href="http://shorturls.redwerks.org/"&gt;this handy wizard&lt;/a&gt;, which I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should come up with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;RewriteRule ^/?wiki(/.*)?$ %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}/w/index.php [QSA,L]
RewriteRule ^/?$ %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}/w/index.php [QSA,L]

RewriteCond %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}%{REQUEST_URI} !-f
RewriteCond %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}%{REQUEST_URI} !-d
RewriteRule ^/?w/images/thumb/[0-9a-f]/[0-9a-f][0-9a-f]/([^/]+)/([0-9]+)px-.*$ %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}/w/thumb.php?f=$1&amp;amp;width=$2 [L,QSA,B]

RewriteCond %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}%{REQUEST_URI} !-f
RewriteCond %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}%{REQUEST_URI} !-d
RewriteRule ^/?w/images/thumb/archive/[0-9a-f]/[0-9a-f][0-9a-f]/([^/]+)/([0-9]+)px-.*$ %{DOCUMENT_ROOT}/w/thumb.php?f=$1&amp;amp;width=$2&amp;amp;archived=1 [L,QSA,B]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That's all great, but old links won't work anymore! Let's fix that by adding this before all the other new RewriteRules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;RewriteRule ^/?wiki/index.php(/(.*))?$ /wiki/$2 [R=301,L]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you should have pretty URLs, and the old-style links should redirect to the new pretty ones too!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Serving identical content on HTTPS and Tor hidden service</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/serving-identical-content-on-https-and-tor-hidden-service.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-03T21:52:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-07-03:serving-identical-content-on-https-and-tor-hidden-service.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently came into an interesting problem- I wanted to serve the same website over the clearnet (the regular internet) using &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; HTTPS, and serve that same content over a Tor hidden service. I assume you have at this point a web server installed (I like Apache) that will successfully serve HTTPS exclusively, but need to add the Tor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Tor. You will want to use &lt;a href="https://www.torproject.org/download/download-unix.html.en"&gt;the Tor Project's repos&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you have the most up-to-date version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit your torrc. It is likely at /etc/tor/torrc. Uncomment the following lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/hiddenService/
HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and/or adjust them accordingly. If you have Apache listening on 443 (for HTTPS) and 80, you should be set with this config.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart Tor to apply new settings. In Debian Wheezy: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo /etc/init.d/tor restart
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your hostname&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo cat /var/lib/tor/hiddenService/hostname
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;should be a string of characters followed by ".onion".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backup your private key&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo cp /var/lib/tor/hiddenService/privateKey /root
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjust your public html folder to move users based on their requested site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable mod_rewrite (if not already)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo a2enmod rewrite
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit (on a default Debian Wheezy apache install) /var/www/.htaccess and add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} !^youronionaddress.onion$
RewriteCond %{HTTPS} !on
RewriteRule (.*) https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The .htaccess does the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the user not requesting the .onion? (Tor hidden services get confused when you talk HTTPS to them)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is HTTPS not on? (If they don't want the .onion, and HTTPS isn't on, we should turn it on!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If conditions 1 and 2 are met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send them back to whatever address they requested, but with HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted this does NOT hide the location of your webserver, but it will allow Tor users to save precious exit node bandwidth by staying inside the Tor network. This is especially neat because changes made on the clearnet will be reflected on the hidden service side, and vice versa.  &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Dota 2 on Xubuntu 13.04</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/dota-2-on-xubuntu-1304.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-20T00:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-06-20:dota-2-on-xubuntu-1304.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Valve was awesome enough to do a native Linux port. &lt;a href="http://store.steampowered.com/app/570/"&gt;Get that version instead!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dota 2 is a really good game. Linux is really good. Out of the box, they don't play nice together. Let's fix that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let's lay out the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am running &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xubuntu 13.04 Raring Ringtail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AMD Phenom(tm) II X4 970 Processor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nvidia GTX 465 with 319.23 drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wine-1.6-rc2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and on all low settings I can easily get a solid 60 FPS in-game, with no dips. Your mileage may vary according to your hardware. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drivers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we need the latest drivers from Nvidia (or ATI, depending on your card). The open source drivers are fine for day-to-day computing, but they don't handle games so well. A rather sexy fellow named Harold Hope made a delightful and very colorful script called &lt;a href="http://smxi.org/site/donations.htm"&gt;sgfxi&lt;/a&gt; that makes installing your latest and greatest binary drivers very easy. Grab a root shell, and run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cd /usr/local/bin &amp;amp;&amp;amp; wget -Nc smxi.org/sgfxi &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod +x sgfxi
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now we need to get into a non-X shell. CTRL-ALT-F1 will do the job nicely. Log in, and run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo sgfxi
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and follow the wizard. You may have to do this once or twice, to remove the old free-as-in-speech drivers before installing the binary drivers. It should be easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Wine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, Wine has improved &lt;em&gt;so much&lt;/em&gt; since I last messed with it around the Gutsy Gibon days. Let's add their PPA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-wine/ppa &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get install wine winetricks
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and wait for all the goodies to download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Wine is installed and situated, we will follow a modified/updated version of the writeup on &lt;a href="http://appdb.winehq.org/objectManager.php?sClass=version&amp;amp;iId=24458"&gt;WineHQ&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what we need to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;WINEPREFIX=~/.wine_dota2/ winecfg
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;will set up a new bottle (haha wine puns) to be our Dota 2 machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Steamy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let's install Steam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;wget http://winetricks.org/winetricks
WINEPREFIX=~/.wine_dota2/ sh winetricks --no-isolate steam
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Follow the wizard, let it update, and log into Steam. Download Dota 2, and add some launch options. Right click Dota 2 in the games list -&amp;gt; properties -&amp;gt; set launch options. These work for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;-novid -console -noforcemaccel -forcemspd -useforcedmparms -high -nod3d9ex -nod3dx -noborder -gl
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;"-novid" disables the intro video. "-console" enables the console. "-noforcemaccel -forcemspd -useforcedmparms" disables mouse acceleration. "-high" starts the game with high CPU priority. "-nod3d9ex -nod3dx -gl" are video tweaks to make it run smoother. "-noborder" starts the game in a borderless window, making alt-tabbing out should the need occur much easier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that with Wine wine-1.6-rc2 and the setup outlined above, I am not affected by any of the bugs on the &lt;a href="http://appdb.winehq.org/objectManager.php?sClass=version&amp;amp;iId=24458"&gt;WineHQ page&lt;/a&gt;. I'm not sure if that's luck of my hardware or improvements in Wine. There is some hitching when the game is loading things (hero selection, playing new sounds for the first time) but once everything is loaded up, the hitching disappears. Very playable, and not booting into Windows anytime soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't have comments on this blog because comments are for jerks and weirdos. Email me if you have questions or comments, and I will edit the post accordingly. glhf!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Encrypting emails and files with OpenPGP</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/encrypting-emails-and-files-with-openpgp.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-26T12:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-05-26:encrypting-emails-and-files-with-openpgp.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was originally written for a blog I co-run with my sister, over at nesasio.com (hence the domain in the screenshots). Actively writing to a single blog is hard enough, let alone multiple. Oh well, here's this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to make sure nobody else saw an email or file except who you wanted? Have you ever wanted to feel like a super spy? Well, through the magic of math (and it is very close to magic!), a system called OpenPGP makes that possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without getting too detailed, OpenPGP and the toolset we will use - GNU Privacy Guard (GPG) uses a type of encryption called "asymmetric" as opposed to symmetric. Symmetric encryption uses the same key for scrambling and unscrambling a message. Asymmetric encryption used two different keys- a public key and private key, each with different purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's figure out what we need to send secret messages. Because of long-standing traditions, encryption scenarios refer to two characters: Alice and Bob. Alice is you, and Bob is who you want to talk to. Let's look at the process we need to follow to safely get secrets to Bob, using a paint metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/500px-Diffie-Hellman_Key_Exchange.gif" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
We will be working on Windows 7, but the process will likely be similar for all versions of Windows, both forward and past.
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation and creating your keypair&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: the common paint&lt;/h4&gt;
First, we need to get the GPG tools! The download can be found at http://gpg4win.org/download.html. We will be using Gpg4win 2.1.0, the most recent stable release. Once downloaded, install it! The defaults should be fine for our purposes. On the screen labeled "Defined trustable root certificate", check to skip configuration. This is related to another encryption type, and will not affect us. You can view the README if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After install, you should see a program called Kleopatra. This is the graphical user interface (GUI) that makes it easier to work with GPG keys and various operations related to GPG. Launch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: your secret color&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Kleopatra is open, it will look fairly empty and boring. We need to create a keypair! Choose File -&amp;gt; New Certificate, and select "Create a personal OpenPGP key pair".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email1.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be prompted for name, email, and a comment should you choose one. These can be anything, so you can use your real name, a fake name, or any bit of text you like! If you want to make a "professional" key pair, it is recommended to use your full, real name. For now, I will create a key pair for this site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email2.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next screen is verifying the information you entered. If it looks right, hit create key. 
Now we have a little work to do. Think of a good, complicated password. I would recommend following xkcd 936:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://sslimgs.xkcd.com/comics/password_strength.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter your password (twice, to make sure you didn't fat finger it), and your key pair will be created!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email3.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encrypting with your new keypair&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email4.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your newly created keypair, you have generated your secret color. We have the mixture of step 3, and need to send our mixture to someone else to do the rest of the steps; to create a common secret. You have to get someone else's mixture - in this case, Bob's blueish mix he made on step 3. Bob can be anyone, Bob is your intended recipient. The recipient could be a friend following this tutorial, or &lt;a href="http://www.gpg4win.org/doc/en/gpg4win-compendium_13.html#sec_publishPerEmail"&gt;the GPG robot known as Adele&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this tutorial, we will talk to Adele.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers, handy things they are, can make our mixture sending, scrambling, and unscrambling easier for us. To that end, we will use the email program Thunderbird. Download it here: &lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/thunderbird/"&gt;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/thunderbird/&lt;/a&gt; The standard defaults will do just fine. Launch Thunderbird after the install finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make Thunderbird the default client for email, newsgroups, and feeds if you so choose. These choices will not affect the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email5.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird, as a way of making money, offers the ability to buy a new email address, of which Mozilla, the people who make Thunderbird, get a little cut. For now, we will skip this and use an existing email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email6.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird is pretty clever here, and should be able to figure out the correct settings for your email address, if you use any sizeable mail service. Hit done, and Thunderbird will retrieve your mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email7.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have our email, we need to add the encryption part! In an attempt to look snazzy, Thunderbird hides the menu bar by default. Press the ALT key, and select Tools -&amp;gt; Add-ons. In the search box in the upper right, type in "enigmail", and the first option should be the right one. Hit install, and restart Thunderbird after it finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email8.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have all the software we need, so now it's time to use it! Press the "Write" button, and let's send an email to Adele!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email9.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we send the email, we have to tell Enigmail to send our mixture to Adele. Assuming you used the same email in your keypair (your secret color) as you did when setting up Thunderbird, it should be smart enough to find the correct key / secret color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email10.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure "Sign Message" is checked, then send your email! Your passphrase box will pop up, to make sure you are who should really be using your secret color. Enter your passphrase, and the mail will go out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email11.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your reply, there will be an important bit of information- Adele's public key - her mixture. At the top of the Thunderbird window, hit "Decrypt", and import her public key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, compose a new email to Adele, but this time, in the OpenPGP menu, check both Encrypt and Sign! And we're done! For anyone that isn't a robot, repeat the process. Send them a signed message, have them reply with a message that they signed, and then sign and encrypt all emails between the pair of you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the decrypted version of the email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email12.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and the scrambled version!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/Email13.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What about files?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already did the hard work with generating and exchanging our keys, so files are pretty simple to work with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I've made this super-secret treasure map I only want Adele to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File1.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right click on the file in Windows Explorer and select "Sign and Encrypt"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File2.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some thinking, the Sign and Encrypt wizard from Kleopatra will appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File3.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, select who you want to encrypt it to. I'll encrypt it to Adele, as I already have her public key handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File4.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I try to continue, Kleopatra gives me this warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File5.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this can be handy in some circumstances, let's encrypt it to myself also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File6.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, select who to sign as. I only have my own private key (secret color), so that seems like the best choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File7.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once that's done, it will process the file(s) you set to be signed and encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File8.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I chose to save the unscrambled file after I made the scrambled one, my folder now looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/openPGPTutorial/File9.png" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the secretTreasure.png.gpg file can only be opened by Adele, and myself. However, she's a robot, and doesn't do file-handling yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is by no means a complete or comprehensive OpenPGP lesson, this is enough to get you up and running, and passing encrypted emails and files back and forth between your friends. The neat part about the key exchange (the paint color exchange) is that the public keys (the mixtures) can be shared openly! As long as your secret key (secret color) stays secret, the system will be (relativley) secure!
If you are interested in more, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public-key_encryption"&gt;I would recommend Wikipedia as a starting point. &lt;/a&gt;There is lots of documentation and articles on public key encryption, especially OpenPGP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Multi-platform, multi-machine Octopressing</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/multi-platform-multi-machine-octopressing.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-29T07:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2013-04-29:multi-platform-multi-machine-octopressing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving to Octopress was a bit of a challenge. Moving from the centralized, easy-to-manage Wordpress ecosystem to the distributed git-managed Octopress was a kick in the head. After acciedently and repeatedly overwriting my own posts and configurations, I decided to clear up the problem once and for all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging on Octopress from  multiple machines, without doing it a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; specific way, does bad, bad things to the blog. To rectify this, I make some scripts to treat the repo as the authoritative copy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Get latest version from repo&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting to work I run this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
git fetch
git reset --hard origin/source
git pull origin &lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ./_deploy
git fetch
git reset --hard origin/master
git pull origin master
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ..
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;or on Windows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;call git fetch origin
call git reset --hard origin/source
call git pull origin source
cd ./_deploy
call git fetch origin
call git reset --hard origin/master
call git pull origin master
cd ..
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;to effectively mirror the existing stuff on the repo, destroying(!) any unpushed changes on my current machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;After writing a post, page, or otherwise updating the site&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
rake generate
git add .
git commit -m &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;updating via script!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git push origin &lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
rake deploy
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;or on Windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;call rake generate
call git add .
call git commit -m &amp;quot;updating via script on Windows!&amp;quot;
call git push origin source
call rake deploy
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This will cleanly and nicely regenerate the static html, and update both the source and site in the repo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setting up a computer to blog from for the first time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git clone git@github.com:username/username.github.com.git
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;username.github.com
username.github.com&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git checkout &lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
username.github.com&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;mkdir _deploy
username.github.com&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;_deploy
username.github.com/_deploy&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git init
username.github.com/_deploy&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git remote add origin git@github.com:username/username.github.com.git
username.github.com/_deploy&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git pull origin master
username.github.com/_deploy&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ..
username.github.com&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After you do all that, make sure you get the latest version from the repo using the scripts in the top of the post.
Hope that helps!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>