<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wyatt Winters | Saving the world one computer at a time</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/feeds/bizlegfoss.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wyattwinters.com/</id><updated>2015-01-27T17:50:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>BIZLEGFOSS@RIT - Week 1</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-27T17:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-01-27:bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whoa, what? An update on this website that has been almost completely stagnant for over a year? Weird!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm somewhat hesitant to write a big long story giving exposition for why this post suddenly appeared, but since my Github account &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; bound to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/FOSSRIT"&gt;RIT FOSSBox's group page&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose it's not all that big of a secret where I go to school. If you're stalking me (or the NSA agent assigned to me) and didn't draw that conclusion, well, there you go, and also, you're bad at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, RIT is the first university in North America to offer &lt;a href="http://magic.rit.edu/foss/"&gt;a minor in Free and Open Source Software&lt;/a&gt;, and I get to be one of the first people to complete it! As such, I am taking "Legal/Business Aspects of FOSS", or BIZLEGFOSS for short (the short name apparently subject to change, but I rather like it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first homework assignment for this course was to make a handful of accounts (blog, github, freenode nickserv, etc), all of which I already had. The final part was to write a blog post about your experience. I could get a little recursive and write about writing this blog post, but that is both silly and time consuming. Hopefully this class will get me back into the blogging mindset. I do have a handful of topics to write about, so perhaps some of those will appear sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry></feed>