<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wyatt Winters | Saving the world one computer at a time</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/feeds/bizlegfoss.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wyattwinters.com/</id><updated>2015-02-10T10:40:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Further adventures in GPL land (BIZLEGFOSS Week 3)</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/further-adventures-in-gpl-land-bizlegfoss-week-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-10T10:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-10:further-adventures-in-gpl-land-bizlegfoss-week-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Assignment 1: "Litreview1"&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;copyleft.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copyleft and the GNU General Public License: A Comprehensive Tutorial and Guide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Chapter 1 specifically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://copyleft.org/guide/" target="_blank"&gt;http://copyleft.org/guide/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are copyright notices dated as late as 2014. So some time in 2014 was the last update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first chapter of this document explains various aspects of software freedom, such
as the GPL, copyleft ideology, and the differences between copyleft and public domain.
It is written in a (relatively) universally understandable way (meaning not
developer-specific).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again, the in-PDF links are fantastic. Some are even to external sources!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"It was once rare that this freedom [the freedom to run] was restricted by even proprietary software; but such is quite common today."&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since most of my computing has been in the post-EULA era, this was interesting
to contemplate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I now have a way better understanding of software freedom vs. public domain software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Copyleft modifies, or 'hacks' copyright law..."&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more people use the term "hack" the less I like seeing it. It's been
muddied and overused, and doesn't really have a concrete meaning anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the wording feels a bit biased. It feels more like a persuasive document,
rather than a general-information document for people trying to learn more about
software freedom and the GPL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I love semantics as much as the next guy, it feels like their definitions of
similar terms are fuzzy at best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there any downsides to licensing one's code under the GPL?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If one wants to make a living by writing code, is the GPL still viable / appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there cases where releasing into the public domain makes more sense than releasing
under the GPL?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While informative, this first chapter wasn't terribly interesting or engaging to read.
Regardless, it is undoubtedly well written, and exhaustively sourced. Given
the inherently dry nature of legal writing, it was more than adequate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>In which I read, watch, and write. (BIZLEGFOSS Week 2)</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/in-which-i-read-watch-and-write-bizlegfoss-week-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-04T13:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-04:in-which-i-read-watch-and-write-bizlegfoss-week-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having to write on this site this often is weird. I had gotten into such a deep
rut of assuming "oh, that's not really worthy of a blog post" about nearly
everything I do (so much so that I hadn't posted anything in like 15 months),
that having to write blog posts (for grades!) this frequently, on a variety of
topics, seems quite strange. Given how relatively surgical and calculated my previous posts have
been, this continues to be a foreign practice to me. Hopefully it will get more
comfortable (or I will stop irrationally worrying about every little thing that
I post. If I go for volume, maybe people won't see the occasional dumb thing I post!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onto the assignments for this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="vidreview0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="#vidreview0"&gt;Assignment 1: "Vidreview0"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/remixeverything" target="_blank"&gt;Kirby Ferguson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingisaremix.info/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://everythingisaremix.info/watch-the-series/" target="_blank"&gt;http://everythingisaremix.info/watch-the-series/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fourth and final part was released 2012-02-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a well done (and exhaustively sourced) documentary-of-sorts about
the history, impacts, and interactions between copyright, patent law, creative
culture, and (as the title would suggest) remixing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The production values were quite good, and it was obvious Mr. Ferguson put
a lot of effort into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm always a fan of not-actually-copyright-notice screens. This one wasn't
particularly funny, but still an excellent use of the trope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no idea why, but the animated sequence at 9:25 at least on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=coGpmA4saEk" target="_blank"&gt;this copy&lt;/a&gt; was maybe my favorite part.
Very Sesame Street-esque.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Youtube version I was linked had some serious compression and artifacting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's common in these documentary / educational type pieces, but I don't
really like the "call to action" bit at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were points that just seemed over-produced - excessive transitions,
sequences with filters for no apparent reason, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The call to action part doesn't go far enough - what can one do to "fix" the issue(s)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While patent trolls are obviously bad, but what are the creator's opinion
about the current state of copyright length?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why was this video done in four parts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I actually enjoyed this quite a bit, despite some of the flaws noted above.
It was educational, engaging, and well made. However, it's difficult to understand
&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it was made, aside from being an educational piece. The creator obviously
feels strongly about the covered topics, but does nothing to encourage the viewer to
get involved in free/open source projects or really take any sort of action.
The ending felt more like it petered out than finished strong...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id="litreview0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="#litreview0"&gt;Assignment 2: "Litreview0"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Software Freedom Law Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Legal Issues Primer for Open Source and Free Software Projects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Intro to the end of Chapter 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.softwarefreedom.org/resources/2008/foss-primer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date on the title page indicates version 1.5.2 was released 2008-06-04&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a FOSS-developer targeted legal primer on a number of issues and
legal topics relevant to FOSS development. It covers copyright, licensing,
organizational structure, patents, and trademarks. It is intended to be a
guideline, not actual cut-and-dried legal advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links in PDFs are awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"If you find yourself feeling the urge to write a new license, it’s a
good sign that you might need to reconsider your approach."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had no idea about the Affero GPL, which seems like an excellent idea.
I wonder why it's not implemented more widely (or maybe I haven't been looking for it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"...send a letter, via as many different methods as possible (at least by email, courier service, and fax)." Fax? Really?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I understand the need, at points the concentration of acronyms got a little
unreadable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The section on copyright for documentation seems oddly short, especially after
they talk up the importance of good documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a simple(r) solution for small projects?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this information globally relevant, or USA specific?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are there so many versions of the GPL, and what are the differences?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's hard to make legal guidelines / information exciting. I understand that.
I suppose this could be far less engaging, but given the nature of the material,
it was engaging enough. More than anything, I'm kind of terrified of FOSS licenses
and how they interact now. No wonder GPL violations (and other license violations)
are so common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry><entry><title>BIZLEGFOSS@RIT - Week 1</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-27T17:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-01-27:bizlegfoss-at-rit-week-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whoa, what? An update on this website that has been almost completely stagnant for over a year? Weird!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm somewhat hesitant to write a big long story giving exposition for why this post suddenly appeared, but since my Github account &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; bound to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/FOSSRIT" target="_blank"&gt;RIT FOSSBox's group page&lt;/a&gt;, I suppose it's not all that big of a secret where I go to school. If you're stalking me (or the NSA agent assigned to me) and didn't draw that conclusion, well, there you go, and also, you're bad at what you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, RIT is the first university in North America to offer &lt;a href="http://magic.rit.edu/foss/" target="_blank"&gt;a minor in Free and Open Source Software&lt;/a&gt;, and I get to be one of the first people to complete it! As such, I am taking "Legal/Business Aspects of FOSS", or BIZLEGFOSS for short (the short name apparently subject to change, but I rather like it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first homework assignment for this course was to make a handful of accounts (blog, github, freenode nickserv, etc), all of which I already had. The final part was to write a blog post about your experience. I could get a little recursive and write about writing this blog post, but that is both silly and time consuming. Hopefully this class will get me back into the blogging mindset. I do have a handful of topics to write about, so perhaps some of those will appear sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bizlegfoss"></category></entry></feed>