<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wyatt Winters | Saving the world one computer at a time</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/feeds/foscis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wyattwinters.com/</id><updated>2015-02-22T14:17:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Social Media is Terrifying</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/social-media-is-terrifying.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-22T14:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-22:social-media-is-terrifying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week of independent study, another medium.com article. This week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dashes.com/anil/about.html" target="_blank"&gt;Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article discusses the post-internet concept of "public," and the numerous
issues surrounding "public" content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I absolutely &lt;em&gt;despise&lt;/em&gt; Gawker and their entire network of sites, so I'm
always glad to see them disparaged by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Facebook chart is terrifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author's end goal is noble, so I respect that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"any of us might throw in a hashtag to gather our thoughts". I never want to
meet anyone who does that. Ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I admit that Twitter and Facebook both have significant "anti-privacy
creep," this article seems to be written from the perspective that Twitter and
Facebook are mandatory. I acknowledge that the regular, average user of social
media is less technical than I; I would like to hope that people understand that
the entirety of their generated content is being indexed and monetized.
Sadly, I know that isn't the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This author apparently doesn't understand private messaging, or other
methods of communication besides Twitter and Facebook. There are a &lt;em&gt;vast&lt;/em&gt;
number of options for less-public communication on the internet, ranging from casual to
paranoid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that the legal system &lt;em&gt;enabled&lt;/em&gt; things like the NSA's dragnet, does
legal reform for privacy / public content issues seem viable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should social media companies be more explicit about their privacy settings
and / or their business models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this problem fixable, and if so, what would be some of the steps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like this article. A number of places in the article talk about consent and the
end user not being able to give it concerning their content. This is
fundamentally flawed - the user gives consent for whatever they post as soon
as they post it. While this may not be ideal, that is the
current state of the social media, and that is unlikely to change any time
soon. One's options are take the good with the bad, or simply don't use
social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that the wide variety of nastiness that can happen
online (swatting, doxxing, harassment, people sending pizzas) is deplorable,
there are also some positives to truly public content - educational value
(there have actually been some fascinating data aggregation projects),
and even the CDC &lt;a href="http://fcw.com/articles/2013/01/25/flu-social-media.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;tracking and predicting the flu&lt;/a&gt;. The internet, specifically social media is a terrifying beast,
but there are a number of cool things that come out of it. I don't think it's the
fault of the services themselves, but rather the small percentage of awful
people who use them for their own, malicious ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all scary, uncharted territory for both society and our legal system.
Who knows if (and how much) it has to get worse before it gets better, if it does at all.
At the end of the day, all of this is opt-in. If you can't deal with the
potential wretchedness that could rear its head, don't sign up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Software: Classification and Preservation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/software-classification-and-preservation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-15T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-15:software-classification-and-preservation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So begins (perhaps a little late into the semester) my adventures in independent study.
In order to finish my FOSS minor at RIT, I am doing an independent study adaptation of a pre-existing course. Because of scheduling conflicts, I cannot take it normally before I graduate, and this is the last requirement to finish out the minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing an independent study version of a class that is very much focused around
reading and group discussion is perhaps a bit suboptimal, but I have been tasked with
writing blog posts / reviews of the readings in lieu of group discussions. It will certainly be an adventure. So, here's the first one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkirschenbaum" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Kirschenbaum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article is the transcript of the opening address at the Library of Congress' &lt;a href="http://www.digitalpreservation.gov/meetings/ndiipp14.html" target="_blank"&gt;Digital Preservation 2014&lt;/a&gt; conference. The author addresses the complexities of software as a "thing", and the difficulties that those complexities introduce to the archival and preservation of software in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a fantastically organized and written piece of prose. I have never given too much thought about the various forms software can take, and, while some of the forms were perhaps a stretch, it was weird to think of software as "epigraphy". It's kind of strange / terrifying to contemplate all the places one's name or data appears on various computer / software systems throughout the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"... is content enough? What counts as context for all our digital content?" This is a pretty serious issue, especially with older software. Trying to play almost any older C64 / Atari 2600 game is neigh-impossible without the manual. Sure, you can dump ROMs and put them on a server without breaking a sweat, but without the associated manuals and documentation, they aren't nearly as useful or interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading this article made me remember to fire up my &lt;a href="http://www.archiveteam.org/index.php?title=ArchiveTeam_Warrior" target="_blank"&gt;ArchiveTeam Warrior&lt;/a&gt; which I hadn't in a while. I might as well put all this spare RIT bandwidth to good use!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That title is pretty bad. Granted, some of the titles I have come up with aren't fantastic, but jeeze. Honorary mention for "Preserving.exe". Yeesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These weren't the author's words, but Thomas Scoville's quote about code and jazz was excruciating. Maybe it's my distaste for jazz, or maybe I haven't been able to have code "flow" as Mr. Scoville describes, but that analogy seems like grasping at very distant straws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "software as clickwrap" section was so short that it seemed like an afterthought. Software distribution does seem to be going increasingly in that direction, so why not discuss it more thoroughly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is software preservation actually as difficult as it is made out to be in this article, or is just a manpower / volume issue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is software a "lesser priority" for the archival / preservation community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the DMCA or other copyright restrictions significantly hindered software archival efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who has been vaguely interested in software archival (and spent a fair amount of time browsing around Archive.org), this was a pretty interesting article. While I don't completely agree with everything presented, it was certainly thought provoking, and perhaps a little distressing. It's alarming to consider the future of all these server based products which likely will cease to exist in their current form at some point. A number of MMO games have disappeared, and can never be played again. It's weird to consider that possibility for a majority of the software tools I use every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry></feed>