<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wyatt Winters | Saving the world one computer at a time</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/feeds/foscis.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://wyattwinters.com/</id><updated>2015-03-08T15:58:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 6</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-6.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-08T15:58:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-08:foscis-week-6.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week's articles are about Net Neutrality. This is somewhat strange, since the FCC &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2015/2/26/8114265/fcc-ruling-net-neutrality-victory-internet-title-ii" target="_blank"&gt;already passed Title II&lt;/a&gt; a couple weeks ago. I suppose this is where taking this class as independent study sort of falls apart, but no matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these articles are relatively short, I'll combine them into one litreview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bogost.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ian Bogost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aprilaser" target="_blank"&gt;April Glaser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Do We Save When We Save the Internet?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;An Open Internet Is Essential to a Free Internet: Why Net Neutrality Should Matter To Everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/05/what-do-we-save-when-we-save-the-internet/370885/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/09/open-internet-essential-free-internet-why-net-neutrality-should-matter-everyone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Bogost's article is dated 2014-05-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is dated 2014-09-10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Bogost's article questions the value of net neutrality, the validity of the openness of the current internet, and the (perceived) negative effects of the internet on daily life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article takes a decidedly opposite stance, spelling out the numerous potential dangers of a non-neutral internet, and (as is typical of the EFF) a call to action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is well cited, and gives specific examples of adverse effects enabled by not having strong net neutrality laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I vehemently oppose almost all of the ideas presented in it, Mr. Bogost's article is quite well written. "The weight and heat of your smartphone in your pocket, silently whimpering for you, a glass and metal kitten with a small, fragile body."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Ms. Glaser's article: "This is a particular concern as more Internet providers expand into content production and distribution. Network discrimination could be used to herd users towards services the ISPs offer, like Verizon’s RedBox, rather than their competitors." - This was always one of the examples I gave when having to explain net neutrality to someone less technically-oriented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ian Bogost must be a profoundly unhappy man. He seems to have little hope, is dismissive, and wants to (apparently) let the internet burn. I feel like this article is largely dominated by emotion, and has immense leaps in logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He seems to think that because giants like Facebook and Twitter exist, that new players can't enter the field. As such, implementing laws that hold that door open (however narrow it may be) are pointless. Sure, you may think things are bad, but why would not at least try to keep things from getting worse? Why would you just give up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This seems to be a common thread in the (admittedly very small) selection of anti-net-neutrality / anti-anonymity articles I have read - the authors seem to think that social media services are mandatory! "Sitting in front of the television, you grasp your iPhone tight in your hand instead of your knitting or your whiskey or your rosary or your lover." I mean, you don't have to. You are more than welcome to pick up any of those other objects (or people, as the case may be).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"You boot a browser and it loads the Yahoo! homepage" - so &lt;em&gt;that's&lt;/em&gt; why this guy is so jaded by the internet. I would be too, if I had to look at Yahoo! every time I loaded my browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the FCC's Title II ruling "save" the internet, or are there still more steps to take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When do the new laws go into effect?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have there been any scientific studies on adverse effects / mental health implications of Mr. Bogost's so called "sins" that he outlines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got most of it out in the "the bad" section, but holy crap, I couldn't agree less with Mr. Bogost. I mean, yeah, there are some super awful parts of the internet, and that sucks. There are also super awful parts of the real world, and that also sucks. I'm not sure giving up on fixing the internet and letting it get monetized and corrupted into an unrecognizable nightmare is the best course of action. If someone's being a jerk, don't engage them, block them, and move on. The benefits of the internet (especially a neutral one) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; outweight the negatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bogost - -3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ms. Glaser's article is much more to my liking, and not only because its ideas are much more in line with my own. It is less emotional (although there are still a handful of weasel words), and provides very clear, specific, and cited examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glaser - 4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSCIS Week 5</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/foscis-week-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-01T19:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-03-01:foscis-week-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two readings this week, so I guess I'll do a section for each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Removing Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/~hsdept/bios/galison.html" target="_blank"&gt;Peter Galison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Removing Knowledge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7Ehsdept/bios/docs/Removing%20Knowledge.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Autumn" 2004, based on the copyright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article discusses the ever-growing domain of the United States' classification of information, and (in no uncertain terms) the numerous downsides of that power creep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"What is the level of damage (“damage,” “serious damage,” or “exceptionally grave damage”)..." That's a steep curve of clasification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Under the Atomic Energy Acts of 1946 and 1954... If I think of a new scheme for channeling X-rays from a fission primary to a thermonuclear secondary and write that idea down, I am (strictu sensu) forbidden from possessing the page I just created." I had no idea about those Acts. How did that make sense to include?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"We probably would not know if a national security secret was as well-kept as the secret of Coca-Cola"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand Dr. Galison has a PhD, but can we reign in the $400 words? I like to think I have a pretty decent vocabulary, but there were a number of words I had to look up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While being somewhat difficult to read, this was &lt;em&gt;not at all&lt;/em&gt; engaging. While Dr. Galison is clearly passionate about this issue, I don't feel particularly swayed by the article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"On the one side, an unaffordable, intractable, holist antiepistemology, on the other a ludicrously naive punctiform one." Well, time for a dictionary, huh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the classified document catalog is massive, what percentage of it is academically / politically / scientifically interesting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any progress on classification reform since this paper was written?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why does storing classified documents cost so much money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe it's because I'm not in the highest-tier of academics, or perhaps I just have other things to worry about, but the issue raised in this paper doesn't interest me at all. Sure, transparency is great and all, but I've found (again, this is probably because I'm not a high-tier academic) most government documents terribly uninteresting. Maybe there's just a certain age you hit and a biological switch fires and you suddenly get super interested in politics? I guess I haven't gotten there yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geeks, Social Imaginaries, and Recursive Publics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Christopher Kelty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geeks, Social Imaginaries, and Recursive Publics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://kelty.org/or/papers/Kelty_CA_Geeks_2005.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2005, based on the copyright and filename.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This document (exhaustively) discusses the anthropologically unique "social imaginary" that is the internet, its users, and the malleability of both the protocols and the discussion topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Boston to Berlin to Bombay (Mumbai)" I love alliteration, even more so when it only accomplished through creative means. Good on you, Professor Kelty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That list of job titles is fantastic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"trying to take something off of the Internet is like trying to take pee out of a pool." I've never actually heard that one before. I'm well familiar with the concept, but never heard it articulated that way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm not a fan of the terms "geek" or "nerd". I feel like they have been co-opted and subsequently bastardized by businessmen trying to ride the "hip new cool wave" of Doctor Who and The Avengers. Seeing it in an academic paper is similarly disgusting to me, however appropriate it may or may not be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"dot.com boom" - I'm not sure that's the standard syntax for that phenomenon...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This falls into a similar trap of the last document - the jargon (in this case anthropological) is so dense that readability for laymen such as myself is compromised. I suppose I'm not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; the intended audience for this document, but still.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would this paper be different if written today, if at all?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the uniqueness of the internet from an anthropological perspective be used to improve / further understanding of other societies / groups / [anthropological unit of people]?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the internet still a subject of intense anthropological interest as it (apparently) was in 2005?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article was definitely more interesting than the last, but not by much. It may just be my cynical, reductionist approach to things, but it seems like the whole thesis of the paper is "People who like the same stuff get in groups to talk about it / make stuff; also, the internet is pretty cool, huh?" Perhaps I'm just jaded about the uniqueness of the internet because I have spent the majority of my life interacting with it. In addition, I've always been a little dismissive of cultural anthropology after I took a &lt;em&gt;startlingly&lt;/em&gt; boring course in it, and this article isn't terribly different. That list of job titles was pretty incredible though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Social Media is Terrifying</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/social-media-is-terrifying.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-22T14:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-22:social-media-is-terrifying.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another week of independent study, another medium.com article. This week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dashes.com/anil/about.html" target="_blank"&gt;Anil Dash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Is Public?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/message/what-is-public-f33b16d780f9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article discusses the post-internet concept of "public," and the numerous
issues surrounding "public" content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I absolutely &lt;em&gt;despise&lt;/em&gt; Gawker and their entire network of sites, so I'm
always glad to see them disparaged by others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Facebook chart is terrifying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author's end goal is noble, so I respect that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"any of us might throw in a hashtag to gather our thoughts". I never want to
meet anyone who does that. Ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I admit that Twitter and Facebook both have significant "anti-privacy
creep," this article seems to be written from the perspective that Twitter and
Facebook are mandatory. I acknowledge that the regular, average user of social
media is less technical than I; I would like to hope that people understand that
the entirety of their generated content is being indexed and monetized.
Sadly, I know that isn't the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This author apparently doesn't understand private messaging, or other
methods of communication besides Twitter and Facebook. There are a &lt;em&gt;vast&lt;/em&gt;
number of options for less-public communication on the internet, ranging from casual to
paranoid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given that the legal system &lt;em&gt;enabled&lt;/em&gt; things like the NSA's dragnet, does
legal reform for privacy / public content issues seem viable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should social media companies be more explicit about their privacy settings
and / or their business models?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this problem fixable, and if so, what would be some of the steps?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't like this article. A number of places in the article talk about consent and the
end user not being able to give it concerning their content. This is
fundamentally flawed - the user gives consent for whatever they post as soon
as they post it. While this may not be ideal, that is the
current state of the social media, and that is unlikely to change any time
soon. One's options are take the good with the bad, or simply don't use
social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that the wide variety of nastiness that can happen
online (swatting, doxxing, harassment, people sending pizzas) is deplorable,
there are also some positives to truly public content - educational value
(there have actually been some fascinating data aggregation projects),
and even the CDC &lt;a href="http://fcw.com/articles/2013/01/25/flu-social-media.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;tracking and predicting the flu&lt;/a&gt;. The internet, specifically social media is a terrifying beast,
but there are a number of cool things that come out of it. I don't think it's the
fault of the services themselves, but rather the small percentage of awful
people who use them for their own, malicious ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all scary, uncharted territory for both society and our legal system.
Who knows if (and how much) it has to get worse before it gets better, if it does at all.
At the end of the day, all of this is opt-in. If you can't deal with the
potential wretchedness that could rear its head, don't sign up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry><entry><title>Software: Classification and Preservation</title><link href="http://wyattwinters.com/software-classification-and-preservation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-15T16:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Wyatt Winters</name></author><id>tag:wyattwinters.com,2015-02-15:software-classification-and-preservation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So begins (perhaps a little late into the semester) my adventures in independent study.
In order to finish my FOSS minor at RIT, I am doing an independent study adaptation of a pre-existing course. Because of scheduling conflicts, I cannot take it normally before I graduate, and this is the last requirement to finish out the minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing an independent study version of a class that is very much focused around
reading and group discussion is perhaps a bit suboptimal, but I have been tasked with
writing blog posts / reviews of the readings in lieu of group discussions. It will certainly be an adventure. So, here's the first one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mkirschenbaum" target="_blank"&gt;Matthew Kirschenbaum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Software, It’s a Thing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3" target="_blank"&gt;https://medium.com/@mkirschenbaum/software-its-a-thing-a550448d0ed3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014-07-24&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article is the transcript of the opening address at the Library of Congress' &lt;a href="http://www.digitalpreservation.gov/meetings/ndiipp14.html" target="_blank"&gt;Digital Preservation 2014&lt;/a&gt; conference. The author addresses the complexities of software as a "thing", and the difficulties that those complexities introduce to the archival and preservation of software in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a fantastically organized and written piece of prose. I have never given too much thought about the various forms software can take, and, while some of the forms were perhaps a stretch, it was weird to think of software as "epigraphy". It's kind of strange / terrifying to contemplate all the places one's name or data appears on various computer / software systems throughout the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"... is content enough? What counts as context for all our digital content?" This is a pretty serious issue, especially with older software. Trying to play almost any older C64 / Atari 2600 game is neigh-impossible without the manual. Sure, you can dump ROMs and put them on a server without breaking a sweat, but without the associated manuals and documentation, they aren't nearly as useful or interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading this article made me remember to fire up my &lt;a href="http://www.archiveteam.org/index.php?title=ArchiveTeam_Warrior" target="_blank"&gt;ArchiveTeam Warrior&lt;/a&gt; which I hadn't in a while. I might as well put all this spare RIT bandwidth to good use!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That title is pretty bad. Granted, some of the titles I have come up with aren't fantastic, but jeeze. Honorary mention for "Preserving.exe". Yeesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These weren't the author's words, but Thomas Scoville's quote about code and jazz was excruciating. Maybe it's my distaste for jazz, or maybe I haven't been able to have code "flow" as Mr. Scoville describes, but that analogy seems like grasping at very distant straws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "software as clickwrap" section was so short that it seemed like an afterthought. Software distribution does seem to be going increasingly in that direction, so why not discuss it more thoroughly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Questions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is software preservation actually as difficult as it is made out to be in this article, or is just a manpower / volume issue?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is software a "lesser priority" for the archival / preservation community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the DMCA or other copyright restrictions significantly hindered software archival efforts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who has been vaguely interested in software archival (and spent a fair amount of time browsing around Archive.org), this was a pretty interesting article. While I don't completely agree with everything presented, it was certainly thought provoking, and perhaps a little distressing. It's alarming to consider the future of all these server based products which likely will cease to exist in their current form at some point. A number of MMO games have disappeared, and can never be played again. It's weird to consider that possibility for a majority of the software tools I use every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4/5 &amp;lt;review increments&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="foscis"></category></entry></feed>